Dr. Oppenheimer.
As we begin, I believe you have
a statement to read
into the record.
Yes, Your Honor.
We're
not judges, Doctor.
No.
Of course.
Members of the security board,
the so-called
derogatory information
in your indictment of me
cannot be fairly understood,
except in the context
of my life and my work.
How
long did he testify?
Honestly, I forget.
The whole hearing took a month.
An ordeal, hmm?
Well, I've only read
the transcripts.
Who'd want to justify
their whole life?
You weren't there?
As chairman, I
wasn't allowed to be.
Are they really going
to ask about it?
- It was years ago.
- Four years ago...
Five.
Oppenheimer still
divides America.
The committee is gonna want
to know where you stood.
Senator Thurmond asked me to say
not to feel that
you're on trial.
Oh, funny, I didn't
till you just said that.
- Really, Mr. Strauss...
- It's Admiral.
Um, Admiral Strauss.
This is a formality.
President Eisenhower has asked
you to be in his cabinet.
Senate really has no
choice but to confirm you.
And if they bring
up Oppenheimer?
When they bring up Oppenheimer,
you answer honestly.
No senator can deny
you did your duty.
It'll be uncomfortable.
Who'd want to justify
their whole life?
Why did you
leave the United States?
I, uh... I wanted to
study the new physics.
Was there nowhere here?
I thought Berkeley
had the leading
theoretical physics department.
Yes. Once I built it.
But first I had to go to Europe.
I went to Cambridge to study
under Patrick Blackett.
Were you happier
there than in America?
- Happier?
- Yes.
No. No, I, uh...
I was homesick, um...
emotionally immature...
troubled by visions
of a hidden universe.
Useless in the lab.
Christ, Oppenheimer.
Have you had any sleep?
Start again.
I need to go to
the lecture, sir.
Why?
It's Niels Bohr.
Damn,
completely forgot.
All right. Let's go.
Oh, no, not you, Oppenheimer.
You finish coating those plates.
You see them?
Don't
forget to clean up!
Quantum physics
is not a step forward,
it is a new way to
understand reality.
Einstein's opened the door,
now we are peering through,
seeing a world inside our world.
A world of energy and paradox
that not everyone can accept.
Yeah, definitely.
Are you all right?
Niels, meet J.
Robert Oppenheimer.
What's the
"J" stand for?
Nothing, apparently.
You were at my lecture.
You asked the only
good question.
No one's
denying his insight.
It's his laboratory work that
leaves a little to be desired.
I heard you
give the same lecture...
At Harvard, yes, and you
asked the same question.
Why ask again?
Hadn't liked your answer.
Did you like it
better yesterday?
A lot.
You can lift the stone
without being ready
for the snake that's revealed.
Now it seems you're ready.
But you don't enjoy the lab?
So get out of Cambridge with
its beakers and potions.
Go somewhere they let you think.
Where?
Göttingen.
- Born?
- Born.
Get to Germany,
study under Max Born.
Learn the ways of theory.
I'll send word.
Wormhole.
How's your mathematics?
Not good enough for the
physicist he wants to be.
Algebra's like sheet music.
The important thing isn't
"Can you read music?"
It's "Can you hear it?"
Can you hear the music, Robert?
Yes, I can.
The senator from Wyoming.
Admiral Strauss, I'm
interested in your relationship
with Dr. J. Robert Oppenheimer.
You met him in 1947?
Correct.
You were commissioner
of the Atomic Energy Commission?
I was, but I-I actually
met Robert in my capacity
as board member of the
Institute for Advanced Study
at Princeton because
after the war, he
was world-renowned
as the great man of physics,
and I was determined
to get him to run the Institute.
Dr. Oppenheimer. An honor.
Mr. Strauss.
It's pronounced "straws."
Oh-ppenheimer,
Oppenheimer.
Whatever way you say it,
they know I'm Jewish.
I'm president of Temple
Emanu-El in Manhattan.
"Straws" is just the
Southern pronunciation.
- Ah.
- Anyway,
welcome to the Institute.
I think you could
be very happy here.
Yes, well, you'll
love the commute.
The position comes
with that house
for you and your wife
and your, is it two children?
Yes, two.
I'm a great admirer
of your work.
And you're a physicist
by training, Mr. Strauss?
I'm sorry, uh,
common room 4:00 tea.
No, I'm not trained in
physics or anything else.
- I'm a self-made man.
- Ah.
- I can relate to that.
- Really?
Yes, my father was one.
And this would be your office.
I'm told he's there
most afternoons.
You know, I've always wondered
why you didn't involve him
in the Manhattan Project.
Greatest scientific
mind of our time.
Of his time.
Einstein published his
Theory of Relativity
more than 40 years ago now.
But never embraced the
quantum world it revealed.
"God doesn't play dice."
Precisely.
You never thought of studying
physics formally, Mr. Strauss?
Well, I had offers, but
I chose to sell shoes.
Lewis Strauss was once
a lowly shoe salesman.
No, just a shoe salesman.
Huh.
- I'd love to introduce you.
- No need.
I have known him for years.
Albert.
What was that? What
did you say to him?
Oh, he's fine.
Mr. Strauss, there
are things in my past
you ought to be aware of.
Well, as chairman of the AEC,
I have access to
your security file.
I've read it.
- You're not worried?
- No.
Why would I be worried
after everything
you've done for your country?
Well, times change, Mr. Strauss.
Well, the purpose
of this institute
is to provide a haven
for independent minds.
That's you. You are
the man for the job.
Well, then I'll consider it.
I'll see you at the
AEC meeting tomorrow.
This is one of the
most prestigious
appointments in the country.
Yes, with a great commute.
That's why I'm considering it.
So,
Dr. Oppenheimer brought
your attention to
his past associations
before you appointed him?
Yes.
And it didn't concern you?
Just then, I was
entirely consumed
with what he must have said
to Einstein to sour him on me.
But later?
Well, we all know
what happened later.
Doctor, your, uh...
your time in Europe,
you seemed to meet
with a wide range
of other countries' physicists.
Yes, that's right.
Any Russians?
None that spring to mind.
If you'll just allow me to
continue with my statement...
Mr. Robb, you'll have ample
opportunity to cross-examine.
After Göttingen, I
moved on to Leiden in Holland
where I first met Isidor Rabi.
Excuse me.
A Yank, lecturing
on the new physics?
This I have to hear.
I'm an American myself.
How surprising.
Um...
Let me know if you need
any help with the English.
Wait, what's he saying?
No, thank you.
It's a long way to Zurich.
You get any skinnier,
we're gonna lose you
between the seat cushions.
I'm Rabi.
Oppenheimer.
I caught your
lecture on molecules.
Caught some of it.
We're a couple of New York
Jews. How do you know Dutch?
Well, I thought
I'd better learn it
when I got here this semester.
You learned enough
Dutch in six weeks
to give a lecture on
quantum mechanics?
Wanted to challenge myself.
Quantum physics wasn't
challenging enough.
- Schvitzer.
- Schvitzer?
Show-off.
Dutch in six weeks, but
you never learned Yiddish?
They don't speak it so
much my side of the park.
Screw you.
You homesick?
Oh, you know it.
Ever get the feeling our kind
isn't entirely welcome here?
Physicists?
'S funny.
Not in the department.
They're all Jewish too.
Eat.
There's a German you
have to seek out.
- Heisenberg.
- Right.
One might be led
to the presumption
that behind the quantum world,
there still hides a real world
in which causality holds,
but such speculation seem to us,
to say it explicitly,
fruitless. Thank you.
Have a great day.
- Wonderful.
- Thank you.
Dr. Oppenheimer.
Oppenheimer, yes.
I liked your paper on molecules.
Probably because
you inspired it.
If I inspire anything
else, let me know.
We could publish together.
I have to get back to America.
Why? There's no one there
taking quantum
mechanics seriously.
That's exactly why.
He's pining for the
canyons of Manhattan.
Canyons of New Mexico.
- You're from New Mexico?
- No.
New York, but my brother
and I have a ranch
outside Santa Fe.
That's the America
I miss right now.
Then it's best you
get home, cowboys.
That's him.
No, me and horses.
I don't think so.
Nice to meet you.
Did you ever encounter
Heisenberg again?
Not in person, no, but, uh...
you might say our paths crossed.
On returning to America,
I accepted positions
at both Caltech
and up at Berkeley.
I got it,
it's all right.
Dr. Lawrence,
I presume?
You must be Oppenheimer.
Yes.
I hear you want to start a
school of quantum theory.
I am starting it. Next door.
- They put you in there?
- I asked for it.
Wanted to be close to
you experimentalists.
Theory will get you
only so far, huh?
We're building a machine
to accelerate electrons.
- Magnificent.
- Would you like to help?
Build it? Oh, no.
No, no.
But I am working on theories
I'd like to test with it.
When do you start teaching?
I've got my first in an hour.
- Seminar?
- Pupil.
One student? That's it?
I'm teaching something no
one here has dreamt of.
But once people start hearing
what you can do with it...
There's no going back.
- Oh. I must have missed the...
- Ah. Lo...
- Mr. Lomanitz?
- Na.
Yeah.
Yes, this is it. Please.
Take a seat.
What do you know about
quantum mechanics?
I have a grasp on the basics.
Then you're doing it wrong.
Is light made up of
particles or waves?
Quantum mechanics
says it's both.
How could it be both?
- It can't.
But it is. It's paradoxical,
and yet, it works.
Now.
Thank you.
Mr. Lomanitz. You're
gonna be okay.
Mr. Snyder.
Now let's consider a star.
A star. A vast furnace
burning in outer space,
fire pushing outwards
against its own gravity.
Balanced.
But if that furnace cools...
and gravity starts
winning, it contracts.
Density increases.
Correct.
Increasing gravity.
Increasing density.
- And?
- It's a vicious cycle until...
what's the limit here?
I don't know.
See where the math takes us.
I guarantee it's somewhere
no one's been before.
Me?
Yes, you. Your math
is better than mine.
Dr. Oppenheimer's file
contained detail of his
activities in Berkeley.
Why would they
have started a file
on Dr. Oppenheimer
before the war?
Well, you'd have
to ask Mr. Hoover.
I'm asking you, Admiral Strauss.
Uh, my assumption is that
it was connected to his, uh,
left-wing political activities.
You shouldn't
let them bring up politics
in the classroom, Oppie.
I wrote that.
Lawrence, you embrace the
revolution in physics.
Can't you see it
everywhere else?
Picasso, Stravinsky,
Freud, Marx.
Well, this
is America, Oppie.
We had our revolution.
Seriously, keep
it out of the lab.
Well, out of the
lab, my landlady
is having a discussion
group tonight. Interested?
I have sampled the
Berkeley political scene.
It's all just
philosophy post-grads
and Communists
talking integration.
You don't care
about integration.
I want to vote for
it, not talk about it.
'Specially on a Friday.
Come on, let's eat.
I'm meeting
my brother there.
And how
would these activities
have come to the attention
of the FBI?
Well, if I remember correctly,
the FBI was taking
license plates
outside suspected
Communist gatherings,
and his name popped up.
- Gotcha!
- Jesus Christ.
- Sorry. Hi, brother.
- Frank.
Uh, you remember Jackie.
Evening.
Let's go. Come.
Right over there,
right over there.
Robert. I want you
to meet Chevalier.
Dr. Haakon Chevalier,
Dr. Robert Oppenheimer.
- Pleasure.
This is my little
brother, Frank.
- And this is...
- Hello.
- Still Jackie.
- Hello, Still Jackie.
Chevalier, you're in languages?
And your reputation
precedes you.
- What have you heard?
- Excuse me.
That you're teaching a radical
new approach to physics
I have no chance
of understanding,
but I hadn't heard
you're a Party member.
- Uh, I'm not.
- Oh, not yet.
Frank and I are thinking of
joining. Just the other day,
- I was saying...
- I support a range of causes.
The
Spanish Civil War?
A democratic republic
being overthrown
by fascist thugs, who wouldn't?
Our government.
They think that socialism is
a bigger threat than fascism.
Not for long.
Look at what the Nazis
are doing to the Jews.
I send funds to colleagues
in Germany to emigrate.
I have to do something.
My own work
is so abstract.
What are you working on?
What happens to the
stars when they die.
Do stars die?
Well, if they do,
they'd cool, then collapse.
In fact, the bigger the star,
the more violent its demise.
The gravity gets so concentrated
it swallows everything.
Everything, even light.
Can that really happen?
The math says it can.
If we can get published,
then perhaps one day,
an astronomer finds one.
But right now, all
I have is theory,
which can't impact
people's lives.
Well, if you're going
to send money to Spain,
do it through the
Communist Party.
They can get it to
the front lines.
Mary sent me with these.
- I'm Jean.
- Robert.
Haakon Chevalier.
The union meeting at
Serber's last month?
Right, right, yes.
Oh, thank you.
Robert here
says he's not a Communist.
Well, then he doesn't
know enough about it.
Oh, I've read Das Kapital,
all three volumes.
Does that count?
It would make you better
read than most party members.
Turgid stuff. There's
some thinking, um,
"Ownership is theft."
- "Property."
- "Property"?
"Property," not "ownership."
I'm sorry, I read it
in the original German.
Well.
It's not about the book.
It's about the ideas. And
you sound uncommitted.
Well, I'm committed
to thinking freely
about how to improve our world.
Why limit yourself to one dogma?
You're a physicist, you
pick and choose rules?
Or do you use the discipline
to channel your
energies into progress?
I like a little wiggle room.
Do you always tow
the party line?
I like my wiggle room too.
What?
Wait, wait, wait.
Unexpected.
- What?
- For a physicist.
You only have a
shelf full of Freud?
Well, actually, my
background's more...
Uh, Jungian?
You know analysis?
When I was in
post-grad at Cambridge,
I had a little trouble.
- I'll bite.
- I tried to poison my tutor.
Did you hate him?
I liked him very much.
You just needed to get laid.
Took my analyst two years,
and I don't think they ever
put it that succinctly.
You have everyone convinced
you're more complicated
than you actually are.
We're all simple souls, I guess.
I'm not.
What's this?
Sanskrit.
You can read this?
I'm learning.
Read this.
Well, in this part,
Vishnu reveals his
multi-armed self...
No.
Read the words.
"And now I am become Death.
Destroyer of worlds."
This'll do.
It'll break before dawn.
Air cools overnight, just
before dawn, it breaks.
Come.
Ah. So, I'm getting married.
- Frank. Congratulations!
- Thank you.
- To Jackie?
Yeah, to Jackie.
The waitress.
Oppie, you're right.
It's lettin' up.
I'm gonna go see if
there's any stars.
All your talk about
the common man,
but Jackie's not good
enough for you, hmm?
Mm-mm.
We join the Party and you can't
- hide your disapproval. Why?
- Oh, now, I...
Is that because that's
supposed to be your thing?
I haven't joined
the Party, Frank.
And I don't think she should
have convinced you to either.
Half of the faculty
is Communist.
Not that half.
I'm your brother, Frank, and
I want you to be cautious.
And I want to wring your neck.
I won't live my life
afraid to make a mistake.
You're happy, I'm happy.
So then I'm happy you're happy
that I'm happy.
I feel
like I could see
one of those dark stars
that you're working on.
You can't. That's
the whole point.
Their gravity swallows light.
It's like a kind
of hole in space.
Is Frank okay?
Yes. He just has
a shitty brother.
It is special here.
When I was a kid,
I thought if I could find a way
to combine physics
and New Mexico,
my life would be
perfect.
Little remote for that.
Yes.
Let's get some sleep.
That mesa
we saw today,
one of my favorite
places in the world.
And tomorrow we'll climb it.
What's it called?
Los Alamos.
I didn't expect
to see you today.
Do I have to make
an appointment?
Hey! Hey,
get back here!
Alvarez?
Oppie! Oppie!
What? What is it?
They've done it.
Hahn and Strassmann in Germany.
They split the uranium nucleus.
How?
Bombard it with neutrons.
It's a
nuclear fission.
They did it, they
split the atom.
It's not possible.
I'm gonna try to reproduce it.
See? Can't be done.
Very
elegant. Quite clear.
- There's just one problem.
- Where?
Next door.
Alvarez did it.
But then look...
these fission pulses,
they're massive.
I've seen 30 of these
in the past ten minutes.
Theory will take
you only so far.
During the process...
extra neutrons boil off,
which could be used to
split other uranium atoms.
Chain reaction.
You're thinkin'
what I'm thinkin'.
You, me, and every other
physicist around the world
who's seen the news.
I'm... what? What
are we all thinking?
A bomb, Alvarez.
A bomb.
I told you, Robert, no
more fucking flowers.
I don't understand
what you want from me.
I don't want anything from you.
Well, you say that
and then you call.
Well, don't answer.
I'll always answer.
Fine.
Just no more flowers.
You're not coming?
You have to know
when you're beaten, Robert.
It's not that simple, Hoke.
Chevalier, good
to see you. It's...
Ah, Barbara, good to see you
and the illustrious
Dr. Oppenheimer.
I'm Eltenton.
- Oh, pleasure.
- Please, please.
Now, might you say a word
about organized labor
on campuses, yes?
Coming through! Coming through!
- F.A.E.C.T.!
- I work at Shell.
We've signed up chemists,
we've signed up engineers,
so why not scientists
in academia?
Oppie!
Oppie! Oppie!
Oppie! Oppie! Oppie! Oppie!
Oppie! Oppie! Oppie!
Teachers are unionized.
Why not professors?
Don't you have somewhere to be?
Lawrence, academics
have rights too.
Look, it's not that.
I've got a group coming.
- Well, I'll sit in.
- Not this one.
Richard. Dr. Bush.
What brings you two up north?
Richard, you tell Ruth
I'll be down to
Pasadena Thursday.
Your paper
on black holes is in!
Oppie!
Where's Hartland? Get
Hartland. Get Hartland.
September 1st, 1939,
the world's gonna
remember this day.
Oh, Hartland. Our
paper, it's in print.
You've been upstaged.
During the Battle of
Britain, I found myself
increasingly out of sympathy
with the
policy of neutrality that
Communists advocated.
Right after Hitler invaded
Russia and we became allies,
these Communist sympathies,
did they return?
No.
I need to make clear that
my changing views on Russia
did not mean a sharp break
from those who held
different views.
For a year or two, and
during a previous marriage,
my wife Kitty had been a
Communist Party member.
Oop!
This way. This is where
I keep the good stuff.
Well, I thought this
was the Tolmans' house.
I live with them
while I'm at Caltech.
Do you two need anything?
We're good, Ruthie.
So, you're a biologist.
Well, somehow I have
graduated to housewife.
Can you explain quantum
mechanics to me?
Seems baffling.
Yes, it is.
Well, this glass,
this drink...
this countertop,
uh, our bodies...
all of it.
It's mostly empty space.
Groupings of tiny energy
waves bound together.
By what?
Forces of attraction strong
enough to convince us
that matter is solid.
Stop my body passing
through yours.
You're married to Dr. Harrison.
Not very.
There is someone that I feel...
Does she feel the same way?
Sometimes. Not enough.
You know, I'm going
to New Mexico.
To my ranch, with friends.
You should come.
I meant with your husband.
Yes, you did.
'Cause you know it won't
make a bit of difference.
Why did you marry him?
I was lost and he was kind.
Lost?
Well, my previous
husband had died, and...
at 28, I wasn't really
ready to be a widow.
- Who was your first husband?
- Nobody.
But my second husband
was Joe Dallet.
He was, um, from
money, like me, but...
he was a union organizer
in Youngstown, Ohio.
Fell hard.
How hard?
Hard enough to spend
the next four years
living off beans and pancakes,
handing out the Daily
Worker at factory gates.
By 36, I just told Joe I
couldn't take it anymore.
Quit the Party and a year later,
I wanted him back, so...
Him, not the Daily Worker.
And he said, "Swell, I'll
meet you on my way to Spain."
He went to fight
for the Loyalists?
And then he went to the
brigades and I waited.
And...
Joe got himself killed
first time he popped his
head out of the trench.
Ideology got Joe
killed. For nothing.
Spanish Republic isn't nothing.
My husband offered
both our futures
to stop one fascist bullet
from embedding
itself in a mudbank.
That's the definition
of nothing.
Seems a little reductive.
Pragmatic.
Now here I am.
Wherever the hell this is.
I didn't want you to
hear it from anyone else.
Least you didn't bring
me flowers.
We both know I'm not
what you want, Jean.
Yeah, but it's a door closing.
No.
Not as far as I'm concerned, no.
You knocked her up, fast work.
Can't keep a good man down.
I meant her.
She knew what she wanted.
What about the husband?
We talked, um,
they're getting a divorce, so...
we can get married before
she starts showing.
How civilized.
You idiot.
This is your community.
You think the rules don't
apply to the golden boy?
Brilliance makes up for a lot.
Don't alienate the only
people in the world
that understand what you do.
One day you might need them.
F.A.E.C.T. MEMBERS
F.A.E.C.T.!
The Federation
of Architects,
Engineers, Chemists
and Technicians.
Lomanitz, what do
you get paid a month?
That's not the point, Lawrence.
What do any of
you have in common
with farm laborers
and dock workers?
Plenty.
Everybody out. Now!
Not you.
What are you doing?
It's a trade union.
Filled with Communists.
So? I haven't joined the Party.
They won't let me bring
you onto the project
because of this shit.
They won't even let me tell
you what the project is.
Oh. I know
what the project is.
Oh, really?
We've all heard about Einstein
and Szilard's
letter to Roosevelt
warning him the Germans
could make a bomb,
and I know what it means for
the Nazis to have a bomb.
Oh, and I don't?
It's not your people
they're herding into camps.
It's mine.
You think that I tell
them about your politics.
The next time you're
coming home from a meeting,
why don't you take a look
in the rearview mirror?
Listen to the sounds
on your phone line
and stop being so goddamn naive.
Why would they care what I do?
Because you're
not just self-important,
you're actually important.
Okay.
Okay. I get it.
If you could just
be a little more...
Pragmatic.
I'll talk to Lomanitz,
I'll talk to the others,
you don't have to
worry. It's done.
Lawrence.
Then welcome to the war.
I filled out my
first security questionnaire
and was informed
that my involvement
with left-wing groups
would not prove a bar to my
working on the atomic program.
Why were
his Communist associations
not seen as a security
risk during the war?
Senator, I can't possibly answer
for security clearance granted
years before I ever met the man.
Fine. What about after?
After the war, Dr. Oppenheimer
was the most respected
scientific voice in the world.
That's why I asked him
to run the Institute,
that's why he advised the
Atomic Energy Commission.
Simple as that.
What are they accusing me of?
I think they just want
to know what happened
between 1947 and 1954
to change your mind
on Oppenheimer's
security clearance.
I didn't. I was
chair of the AEC,
but it wasn't me that brought
the charges against Robert.
- Who did?
- Some former staff member
of the Joint
Congressional Committee.
He was a rabid
anti-Communist named Borden.
He wrote to the FBI
demanding they take action.
The FBI? Why not go
to the AEC, direct?
Why get caught holding
the knife yourself?
What did Borden have
against Oppenheimer?
This was the McCarthy Era.
People hounded out of jobs
for any hint of red. And then,
reading Oppenheimer's
security file,
his Communist brother,
sister-in-law,
fiancée, best friend, wife.
That's before we even get
to the Chevalier incident.
But how would Borden have access
to Oppenheimer's security file?
Because somebody gave it to him.
Somebody who wanted
Robert silenced.
- Who?
- Who knows?
Robert didn't take
care not to upset
the power brokers in Washington.
His opinions on the
atom became definitive
and he wasn't always patient
with us mere mortals.
I came in for plenty
of harsh treatment.
There was an AEC vote
on the export of
isotopes to Norway,
and they drafted in Robert
to make me look like a fool.
But,
Dr. Oppenheimer,
we've already heard from
Admiral Strauss that
these isotopes could be
useful to our enemies
in the production
of atomic weapons.
Congressmen,
you could use a shovel
in making atomic weapons.
In fact, you do.
You could use a bottle of beer
in making atomic weapons.
In fact, you do.
I say isotopes are less useful
than electronic components
but more useful than a sandwich.
Genius is no
guarantee of wisdom.
How could this man who
saw so much be so blind?
Kitty?
Kitty, the project...
I'm in. I'm in.
Let's celebrate.
Shouldn't you go to him?
I have been going to
him all fucking day.
Come here, darling.
I don't know how to say this.
I'm... I'm ashamed to ask.
Anything.
Take Peter.
- Sure.
- No, for-for a while, Hoke.
A while.
Does Kitty know you're here?
Yes, of course she knows.
Of course she knows.
We're awful people.
Selfish, awful people.
Forget I asked.
Selfish, awful people,
they don't know they're
selfish and awful.
Sit, sit, sit.
Robert, you see beyond
the world we live in.
There is a price to
be paid for that.
Of course we'll help you.
Everything's
changing, Robert.
Having a child was
always going to change...
No, the world, it's pivoting
in some new direction.
It's reforming.
This is your moment.
We're putting together a
group to study feasibility...
"We" shouldn't be doing
anything. You should.
Lawrence won't get this done.
Or Tolman or Rabi. You will.
Who are the uniforms?
I thought you might know.
Dr. Oppenheimer.
I'm Colonel Groves.
This is Lieutenant
Colonel Nichols.
Have that dry-cleaned.
Well, if that's how you
treat Lieutenant Colonel,
I'd hate to see how you
treat a humble physicist.
Ah, if I ever meet
one, I'll let you know.
Ouch.
Theaters of combat
all over the world,
but I have to stay
in Washington.
- Why?
- I built the Pentagon.
The brass likes it so much
they made me take over
the Manhattan Engineer District.
Which is?
Oh, don't be a smart ass. You
know damn well what it is.
You and half of every
physics department
across the country.
That's problem number one.
I thought problem
number one would be
securing enough uranium ore.
1,200 tons bought the
day I took charge.
Processing?
Just broke ground at
Oak Ridge, Tennessee.
Now I'm looking for
a project director.
And my name came up?
Nope.
Even though you brought
quantum physics to America.
Which made me curious.
What have you found out?
You're a dilettante,
a womanizer,
a suspected Communist...
I'm a New Deal Democrat.
I said "suspected."
Unstable, theatrical,
egotistical, neurotic...
Nothing good, no?
Not even "he's
brilliant, but..."
Well, brilliance is
taken for granted
in your circle, so no.
No, the only person who
had anything good to say
was Richard Tolman.
Tolman thinks you
have integrity,
but he also strikes me as a guy
who knows more about
science than people.
Yet here you are. You
don't take much on trust.
I don't take anything on trust.
Why don't you have
a Nobel Prize?
Why aren't you a general?
They're making me one for this.
Perhaps I'll have the same luck.
A Nobel Prize for making a bomb?
Alfred Nobel invented dynamite.
So how would you proceed?
You're talking
about turning theory
into a practical weapons system
faster than the Nazis.
Who have a 12-month head start.
Eighteen.
How could you
possibly know that?
Our fast neutron
research took six months.
The man they've
undoubtedly put in charge
will have made that
leap instantly.
Who do you think
they put in charge?
Werner Heisenberg.
He has the most
intuitive understanding
of atomic structure
I have ever seen.
- You know his work?
- I know him.
Just like I know Walther
Bothe, von Weizsäcker, Diebner.
In a straight race,
the Germans win.
- We've got one hope.
- Which is?
Anti-Semitism.
What?
Hitler called quantum
physics "Jewish science."
Said it right to
Einstein's face.
Our one hope is that Hitler
is so... so blinded by hate
that he's denied Heisenberg
proper resources,
because it'll take
vast resources.
Our nation's best
scientists working together.
Right now, they're scattered.
Which gives us
compartmentalization.
All minds have to
see the whole task
to contribute efficiently.
Poor security may
cost us the race.
Inefficiency will.
The Germans know
more than us anyway.
The Russians don't.
Remind me, who are
we at war with?
Somebody with your past
doesn't want to be seen
downplaying the importance
of security from our
Communist allies.
Point taken. But, no.
You don't
get to say "no" to me.
It's my job to say "no"
to you when you're wrong.
So you have the job now?
Uh, I'm considering it.
I'm starting to see where
you got your reputation.
My favorite response,
"Oppenheimer couldn't
run a hamburger stand."
I couldn't.
But I can run the
Manhattan Project.
There's a way to
balance these things.
Keep the Rad Lab here at
Berkeley under Lawrence.
Met Lab in Chicago,
under Szilard.
Large-scale refining, where
did you say? Tennessee.
- And Hanford.
All America's industrial might
and scientific innovation,
connected by rail.
Focused on one goal.
One point in space and time.
And it comes together here.
A secret laboratory. In
the middle of nowhere,
secure, self-sufficient,
equipment, housing, the works.
Keep everyone there
until it's done.
It'll need a school,
stores, a church.
Why?
If we don't
let scientists
bring their families,
we'll never get the best.
You want security, build
a town, build it fast.
Where?
Welcome to Los Alamos.
Now, there's a boys school
we'll have to commandeer,
and the local Indians come
up here for burial rites.
But, apart from that, nothing.
Forty miles. Any direction.
Enough to find the perfect spot.
- For?
- Success.
Build him a town. Fast.
Let's go recruit
some scientists.
Why would I leave my family?
I told you, you can
bring your family.
I'm not a soldier, Oppie.
A soldier? He's a general.
I've got all the soldier I need.
What can I tell them?
Heisenberg, Diebner,
Bothe and Bohr.
What do these men
have in common?
The greatest minds
on atomic theory.
- Yes, and?
- Uh...
As much as you like,
until you feel my
boot on your balls.
You know isotopes and
you know explosives
better than anyone in the world.
But you can't tell
us what you're doing?
- I don't know.
- The Nazis have them.
- Niels Bohr's in Copenhagen.
- Under Nazi occupation.
Did they stop printing
newspapers in Princeton?
Why would we go to
the middle of nowhere
for who knows how
long?
For a year or two. Or three.
Uh, General, could
you give us a moment?
It's about unleashing
the strong force...
before the Nazis do.
Oh, my God.
Niels won't work for the Nazis.
No, never.
But while they
have him, we don't.
That's why I need you.
Why would you think I'd do that?
"Why?" "Why?"
How about because this is the
most important fucking thing
to ever happen in the
history of the world.
How about that?
Fuck.
They are not gonna let
me onto this project.
And failing a security
check is not gonna be good
for a career, even
after the war.
So you're a fellow
traveler. So what?
This is a national emergency.
I've got some skeletons,
they put me in charge.
They need us.
Until they don't.
Is there any chance of
getting Bohr out of Denmark?
Nah, no dice. I checked
with the British.
Until we get Allied boots
back onto the continent,
there's just no way.
Is he that important?
How many people do you know
who proved Einstein wrong?
You know, it really would
be quicker to take a plane.
No, plane's too risky.
Country needs us.
The Harvard guys,
they say the building's too
small for the cyclotron.
Get them together
with the architects.
When's this place
supposed to open?
Two months.
Robert, you're the
great improviser,
but this...
you can't do in your head.
Four divisions.
Experimental, Theoretical,
Metallurgical, Ordnance.
Who's running Theoretical?
I am.
That's what
I was afraid of.
You're spread too thin.
So you take Theoretical.
I'm not coming here, Robert.
Why not?
You drop a bomb and it falls
on the just and the unjust.
I don't wish the culmination
of three centuries of physics
to be a weapon of
mass destruction.
Izzy.
I don't know if we can be
trusted with such a weapon.
But I know the Nazis can't.
We have no choice.
Then...
the second thing you'll
have to do is appoint
Hans Bethe to run the
Theoretical division.
Wait, what was the first?
Take off that
ridiculous uniform.
You're a scientist.
Groves is insisting we join.
Tell Groves to go
shit in his hat.
They need us for who
we are. So be yourself.
Only better.
This is the only key.
And Teller's already here.
Shall I just show him in?
No, let's wait for the others.
Let's get started.
Hello, Edward.
Yes.
Gentlemen, so, we will work here
until the T-section at
Los Alamos is finished.
- Edward, can I please...
- It is more important.
When I calculated
the chain reaction,
I found a rather
troubling possibility.
No.
But this can't be right.
Show me how you did
your calculations.
Yes.
It's exponential.
No. No, no, no. No.
This is fantasy.
Teller's calculations
can't be right.
Do them yourself while
I go to Princeton.
- What for?
- To talk to Einstein.
Well, there's not much common
ground between you two.
That's why I should
get his view.
- Albert.
- Hmm?
Ah. Dr. Oppenheimer.
Well, have you met Dr. Gödel?
We walk here most days.
Trees are the most
inspiring structures.
Albert, might I have a word?
Of course. 'Scuse me, Kurt.
You know, some days,
Kurt refuses to eat.
Even in Princeton.
He's convinced that the
Nazis can poison his food.
Mm.
Hmm? Huh.
Wha...
Whose... Whose work is this?
Teller's.
What do you take it to mean?
Neutrons smash into nucleus,
releasing neutrons to
smash into other nuclei.
Criticality, a
point of no return,
massive explosive force.
But this time, the chain
reaction doesn't stop.
It would ignite the atmosphere.
When we detonate
an atomic device,
we might start a
chain reaction that...
destroys the world.
So here we are, hmm?
Lost in your quantum
world of probabilities
and needing certainty.
Can you run the
calculations yourself?
About the only thing
you and I have in common is
a disdain for mathematics.
Who's working on
this in-in Berkeley?
Hans Bethe.
Well, he'll get to the truth.
And if the truth
is catastrophic?
Then you stop.
And you share your
findings with the Nazis.
So neither side
destroys the world.
Robert.
This is yours, not mine.
Teller's wrong.
He's wrong.
When you know Teller's
critical assumptions,
the real picture emerges.
Bottom line?
The chances of an
uncontrolled nuclear reaction
are near zero.
Near zero.
- Oppie, this is good news.
- Mm.
Can you run them again?
No, you'll get the same answer.
Till they actually detonate
one of these things,
the best assurance you're
going to get is this.
Near zero.
Theory
will take you only so far.
- Mm.
- Hello!
- Hello, you.
- Hi.
We missed him.
You want to adopt?
She's kidding.
We wanted to see
you before we left.
For parts unknown.
You know who
I ran into the other day?
Eltenton.
Oh.
The chemist from
Shell? The union guy?
Yeah. He...
The, uh, F.A.E.C.T. guy.
He was moaning about how
we're handling the war.
How so?
Lack of cooperation
with our allies.
Apparently our
government's not sharing
any research with the Russians.
Well, he said,
"Most scientists think
the policy is stupid."
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
He mentioned that if anyone
had anything they
wanted to pass on,
uh, going around
official channels,
that he could help.
That would be treason.
Yes, of course.
I just thought you should know.
The brat is down.
Where are the martinis?
Coming right up.
Conversation ended there.
Nothing in our
long-standing friendship
would have led me to believe
that Chevalier was actually
seeking information,
and I am certain
that he had no idea
of the work in
which I was engaged.
It has long been clear to me
that I should have reported
this incident at once.
The
Oppenheimer situation
highlights the tension
between scientists
and the security apparatus.
In hopes of learning
how the nominee handled
such issues during
his time at the AEC,
we'll have a scientist
appearing before the committee.
Who are they bringing in?
They hadn't said.
Mr. Chairman,
if I may,
I'm nominated for
Commerce Secretary.
Why seek the opinion
of scientists?
This is a Cabinet post, Admiral.
We seek a wide range of opinion.
Well, I'd like to know the name
of the scientist testifying.
I'd like the chance
to cross-examine.
This is not a court.
Formality, huh?
No
presidential Cabinet nominee
has failed to be
confirmed since 1925.
This is just how
the game is played.
It's in the bag, Lewis.
So play nice.
They bring in a
scientist, so what?
You don't know scientists
like I do, Counselor.
They resent anyone who
questions their judgment,
especially if you're
not one of them.
I was chair of the AEC.
I'm easy to blame for
what happened to Robert.
We can't have the
Senate thinking
the scientific community
doesn't support you, sir.
Or should we pivot?
- To what?
- And embrace it.
"I fought Oppenheimer,
and the US won."
I-I don't think we
need to go there.
Isn't there someone we can call
who knows what really happened?
- Teller.
- He'll make an impression.
Can you get the name of the
scientist they've called?
- Probably.
- Find out if he was
based in Chicago or Los
Alamos during the war.
Why does that matter?
Well, if he was
based in Chicago,
then he worked under
Szilard and Fermi,
not the cult of
Oppie at Los Alamos.
Robert built that damn place.
He was founder, mayor, sheriff,
all rolled into one.
All it needs is a saloon.
There's no kitchen.
Really? We'll fix that.
Barbed wire, guns.
Oppie.
We're at war, Hans.
Halifax. 1917.
A cargo ship carrying munitions
explodes in the harbor.
A vast and sudden
chemical reaction.
The biggest man-made
explosion in history.
Now let's calculate how
much more destructive
it would have been
if it were a nuclear
and not a chemical reaction.
Expressing power in
terms of tons of TNT.
But it will be thousands.
Well, then kilotons.
Using U-235,
- the bomb will need a...
- Uh-uh.
Sorry. Gadget will
need a 33-pound sphere
about this size.
Or using plutonium,
the ten-pound sphere.
Here's the amount of uranium
Oak Ridge refined
all of last month.
And the Hanford plant
made this much plutonium.
Now, if we can
enrich these amounts,
we need a way to detonate them.
Are we boring you, Edward?
A little bit, yes.
May I ask why?
We all
entered this room
knowing a fission
bomb was possible.
How 'bout we leave it
with something new?
Such as?
Instead of uranium or plutonium,
we use hydrogen.
- Heavy hydrogen.
- Hydrogen.
Deuterium. You see?
We compact the atoms together
under great pressure to
induce a fusion reaction.
Then we'll get not kilotons,
but megatons.
A big
fission reaction...
Okay, hang on, hang on.
So how do you generate enough
force to fuse hydrogen atoms?
A small fission bomb.
There we are.
Well, since we're going
to need one anyway,
can we get back to
the business at hand?
The isotopes issue
wasn't your most important
policy disagreement
with Dr. Oppenheimer.
It was the hydrogen
bomb, wasn't it?
Uh, as colleagues,
we agreed to disagree
on a great many things, uh,
and, well, one of them
was the need for an
H-bomb program, yes.
Thanks for convening
on short notice.
I can't believe it.
Well, here we are.
Catch me up. What do we know?
One of our B-29s over
the North Pacific
has detected radiation.
Do we have the filter papers?
There's no doubt what this is.
White House says
there's a doubt.
Wishful thinking, I'm afraid.
Are those the long-range
detection filter papers?
It's an atomic test.
The Russians have a bomb.
We're supposed to be years
ahead of them, but some...
What were you guys
doing at Los Alamos?
Wasn't security tight?
Of course it was.
You weren't there.
- It was...
- Forgive me, Doctor...
but I was there.
We can now consider
the actual mechanics
of detonation.
Any ideas?
I call
this "shooting."
We fire a chunk of fissionable
material into a larger sphere
with enough force to
achieve criticality.
What do we think? Anyone?
I've been
thinking about implosion.
Explosives around the
sphere blast inwards,
crushing the material.
I'd like to
investigate that idea.
I'll talk to Ordnance,
get you blowing things up.
Progress?
Nice to see you too.
Meet the British contingent.
Dr. Oppenheimer, Klaus Fuchs.
How long have you been British?
Since Hitler told
me I wasn't German.
Uh-huh. Come, welcome
to Los Alamos.
School's up and running.
Bar. Always running.
And I thought of a way
to reduce support staff.
- Is that...
- Mrs. Serber, yes.
I've offered jobs
to all the wives.
Admin, librarians, computation.
We cut down on staff,
keep families together.
- Are these women qualified?
- Don't be absurd.
These are some of the brightest
minds in our community.
And they're already
security cleared.
I've informed General
Groves you've been holding
cross-divisional
open discussions
- on a nightly basis.
- Shut them down.
Compartmentalization is the
key to maintaining security...
It's only the top men.
Who presumably communicate
with subordinates.
These men aren't stupid.
- They can be discreet.
- I don't like it.
You don't like anything enough
for that to be a fair test.
Once a week. Top men only.
I'd like to bring
my brother here.
No.
Uh, Nichols...
I still haven't heard
that my security clearance
- has been approved.
- It hasn't.
We're going to Chicago tomorrow.
No, you should wait.
You are aware that the Nazis
have a two-year head start.
Dr. Oppenheimer, the fact
that your security clearance
is proving difficult to
obtain is not my fault.
It's yours.
May not be your fault,
but it's your problem.
Because I'm going.
And how many
people were in these, uh,
- open discussions?
- Too many.
Compartmentalization was
supposed to be the protocol.
We were in a race
against the Nazis.
And now the race is
against the Soviets.
- Not unless we start it.
- Robert.
They just fired a starting gun.
What's the nature of the
device they detonated?
The data
indicates it may have been
a plutonium implosion device.
Like the one you
built at Los Alamos.
The Russians have a bomb,
Truman needs to
know what's next.
What's next? Arms talks.
- Arms talks.
- Obviously.
What about the Super?
Does Truman even know about it?
Did we brief him on that?
Not specifically.
We still don't know
if a hydrogen bomb's
technically feasible.
Right, my understanding is
that Teller proposed it?
- Yes.
- At Los Alamos?
Teller's designs have always
been wildly impractical.
You'd have to
deliver by ox cart.
- Not airplane.
- Oppie.
I'm sorry, Dr. Lawrence,
you want to comment?
No.
Because if it can
put us ahead again,
the President of
the United States
needs to know about it.
And if the Russians
know about it already,
from a spy at Los Alamos,
then we've gotta get going.
There's no proof there
was a spy at Los Alamos.
Robert.
They put it under
the football stadium?
The field's not in use anymore.
Just as well.
- Oppie.
- Dr. Fermi.
I hear you got a little town.
Yes. Come and see.
Who could think straight
in a place like that? Huh?
Everybody will go crazy.
Thank you for the vote
of confidence, Szilard.
Do we really... do we really
need that in the notes?
When are you going
to try it out?
We did.
The first self-sustaining
nuclear chain reaction.
Didn't Groves tell you?
No.
One at a time,
please, one at a time.
Dr. Oppenheimer?
I tried Personnel. They
asked if I could type.
Can you?
Harvard forgot to teach that
on the graduate
chemistry course.
Condon, put Mrs. Hornig
here on the plutonium team.
What the hell were
you doing in Chicago?
Visiting the Met?
- Why? Why?
- Well, you can't talk to...
Because we have every right...
You have just the
rights that I give you.
No more, no less.
We are adults trying
to run a project here.
This is ridiculous.
Tell him.
Compartmentalization is
the protocol we agreed to.
Enough of this madhouse.
Nobody can work under
these conditions.
You know what,
Generalissimo? I quit.
Thanks for nothing.
Better
off without him.
Aren't you more concerned
about his discretion out there?
We'll have him killed.
I was just kidding.
- No, he hates me, not America.
- You know, General,
not everyone has levers
to pull like mine.
I don't think I understand.
You didn't hire me
despite my left-wing past.
You hired me because of it.
So you could control me.
Well, I'm not that subtle.
I'm just a humble soldier.
You're neither humble
nor just a soldier.
You studied engineering at MIT.
Guilty as charged.
Well, now we
understand each other,
perhaps you can get me
my security clearance
so I can perform
this miracle for you.
General
Groves, were you aware
of Dr. Oppenheimer's
left-wing associations
when you appointed him?
I was aware that there
were suspicions about him.
I was aware he
had a very extreme
liberal background.
In your opinion, would
he ever consciously
commit a disloyal act?
I would be amazed if he did.
So you had complete
confidence in his integrity.
At Los Alamos, yes,
which is where I
really knew him.
General, did your
security officers
on the project advise you
against the clearance
of Dr. Oppenheimer?
They could not and would not
clear him until I insisted.
And it's safe to say that you
had a pretty good knowledge
of Dr. Oppenheimer's
security file.
I did.
Well, then there's only
really one question
I need answered here today.
In light of the
current AEC guidelines,
would you clear
Dr. Oppenheimer today?
Do you have the guidelines?
Under current
AEC guidelines,
would you clear
Dr. Oppenheimer today?
Physics and New
Mexico, huh?
My God. What a trek.
That's why you need a liaison.
I'm appointing Lomanitz.
You're gonna be okay.
This way, gentlemen.
- Dr. Lawrence.
- Leslie.
I'd like to remind you what
we talked about in Berkeley.
Compartmentalization. I
understand completely.
Okay.
Thank you.
Greetings
from Berkeley.
I am here to update
you on our progress
and solicit your input.
To do so, I am going
to have to share
a few things that General
Groves told me not to.
Sorry, General, I
said I understood,
not that I agreed.
'Kay.
Gentlemen, to business.
There were rumors of
espionage at Los Alamos.
Unsubstantiated.
I'm told
that there were
Communists on the project.
We didn't knowingly
employ any Communists.
I just want to know,
were any of them involved
in discussions of the Super?
I seem to remember you demanding
your brother come to Los Alamos.
My brother had left
the Party by then.
What about Lomanitz?
Lomanitz was never
employed at Los Alamos.
He was a liaison.
Our security was tight,
as former Colonel
Nichols well knows.
Our security was as
tight as it could be
given the
personalities involved,
but attempts were made.
What is that supposed to mean?
We've all read his file here.
Do we need to talk
about Jean Tatlock?
Or the Chevalier incident?
'Scuse me.
That's
Lomanitz, line one.
Hello, Rossi.
What? O-Okay, just calm down.
There's been another screw-up.
Lomanitz just got drafted.
- We are at war, Doctor.
- Don't be an asshole, Nichols.
We need this kid.
Fix it, will you?
It wasn't a mistake.
Your friend Lomanitz
has been trying
to unionize the Radiation Lab.
He promised to quit all that.
Well, he hasn't.
Security officer at
Berkeley's concerned about
Communist infiltration
through that union,
- the F.A...
- F.A.E.C.T.
While I'm there next week,
I'll drop in to see him.
Your Q clearance came through.
It's important you
not maintain or renew
any questionable associations.
Doctor, did you
think social contacts
between a person engaged
on secret war work
and Communists was dangerous?
My awareness of the danger
would be greater today.
I mean, it's fair to say
that during the war years,
you felt that such contacts
were potentially dangerous.
Were conceivably
dangerous, yes.
I mean, really,
known Communists.
Look...
I've had a lot of secrets
in my head for a long time.
Doesn't matter who
I associate with.
I don't talk about
those secrets.
You said
in your statement
that you had to see
Jean Tatlock in 1943.
You left.
Not a word.
What did you think
that would do to me?
I wrote.
Pages of nothing.
Where did you go?
- I can't tell you.
- Why not?
Because you're a Communist.
Why did you have to see her?
Because she had
indicated a great desire
to see me before we left.
At that time, I couldn't,
but I felt that
she had to see me.
She was undergoing
psychiatric treatment.
She was extremely unhappy.
Did you find out why
she had to see you?
Because she was still
in love with me.
Spent the night
together, didn't you?
Yes.
You drop in and out of my life,
and you don't have
to tell me why.
Now that's power.
Not that I enjoy.
I'd rather be here
for you as you need.
But you have other
priorities now.
I have a wife and child.
That's not what either
of us is talking about.
Jean.
You asked me to come.
And I'm glad I did.
But I can't see you again.
But what if I need you?
You said you would
always answer.
Not a word?
Did you think that
consistent with good security?
As a matter of fact, it was.
Not a word.
When did you
see her after that?
I never saw her again.
I can make the last
train back to Princeton.
Kitty, I didn't say anything
that I hadn't already told you.
Today you said it to
history, didn't you?
This is a closed hearing.
If they don't
release the transcript,
- I'm sure you will.
- I was under oath.
Well, you were
under an oath for me
when you went to see Jean.
You know, you...
you sit there, day after day,
letting them pick
our lives to pieces.
Why won't you fight?
Robert, I'm
not putting her up there.
Dr. Oppenheimer, it's an
honor. Please, take a seat.
No need, um, I just wanted
to check whether I should
talk to Lomanitz while I'm
here, given your concerns.
Well, I'd say that's really
up to you, Professor,
- but I'd be cautious.
- Uh-huh. Understood.
Oh, and, um,
as regards to the union,
I wanted to give you
a heads-up on a...
on a man named Eltenton.
A heads-up?
Yes, just that he might
merit watching is all.
Well, I'd love to
get more details.
Well, I... I have
an appointment now
and I leave early tomorrow.
Well, come back as
early as you like.
Since you haven't time now.
You went back the next morning.
I did, I had to, really.
This time, there
was another man.
He said his name's Pash.
Pash. You met Colonel Pash?
Colonel Pash,
could you please read
from your memo
dated June 29, 1943?
"Results of surveillance
conducted on subject
"indicate further possible
Communist Party connections.
"Subject met with and
spent considerable time
"with one Jean
Tatlock, Communist,
the record of whom is attached."
The subject being
Dr. Oppenheimer?
- Yes.
- Whom you had not met?
Not then,
but soon after.
He's the head of
security for the project.
Shouldn't I know him?
No, he should know you.
I would never put you
in a room with Pash.
Why not?
When Pash first
heard about Lomanitz,
he told the FBI he
was gonna kidnap him,
take him out on a boat
and interrogate him
in the Russian manner.
General Groves has placed in
me a certain responsibility,
and it's like having a
child who I can't see.
- Ah.
- By remote control.
So to actually meet you is...
I won't take up too
much of your time.
No, no, not at all.
Whatever time you choose.
Mm. Mr. Johnson told
me of a conversation
you had yesterday in
which I'm very interested.
It's had me worried all day.
Yes, well, I didn't
want to talk to Lomanitz
without authorization.
That's not the particular
interest that I have.
It's something a
little bit more...
well, in my opinion,
more serious.
Now, when the FBI pointed
out that such information
wouldn't be admissible in
court, Pash made it clear
he had no intention of leaving
any witness left to prosecute.
Now, the FBI talked him down,
but that's the man
you're dancing with.
I gather you've heard
there are other parties
interested in the work
of the Radiation Lab.
A man attached to
the Soviet Consul
indicated, through
intermediate people,
to people on this project,
that he was in a position
to transmit information.
Oh, why would anyone on the
project want to do that?
Frankly, I can see that
there might be an argument
for the Commander-in-Chief
informing the Russians...
they're our allies after all...
but I don't like the idea of
it going out the back door.
It might not hurt to be
on the lookout for it.
And you said that to Pash?
I was trying to put it
in a context of
Russia's not Germany.
Boris Pash is the son of
a Russian Orthodox bishop.
Born here, but in 1918,
he went back to Russia
to fight the Bolsheviks.
This is a man who has killed
Communists with his own hands.
I'm not the judge of who should
or should not have information.
It's my business to stop it
from going through illegally.
Would you be a
little more specific?
There's a man whose
name was mentioned to me
a couple of times. Eltenton.
Uh, I believe he's a
chemist who works at Shell.
He talked to a friend of his
who's an acquaintance of
someone on the project.
And you thought Pash would
be satisfied with that?
I was attempting to
give them Eltenton
without opening a can of worms.
I told them a
cock-and-bull story.
Did you lie to
General Groves too?
No. I admitted to him
that I'd lied to Pash.
Do you recall
this conversation
about the Chevalier incident?
I've seen so many
versions of it. Um...
Wasn't confused before,
but I'm certainly
getting there now.
And what
was your conclusion?
That he was under
the influence of
the typical American
schoolboy attitude
that there's something wicked
about telling on a friend.
Well, now.
Might we know through
whom the contact was made?
That would in... involve people
who are not to be
involved in this.
Is that someone a
member of the project?
A member of the faculty, yes,
but not in the project, no.
Ah.
So Eltenton made his approach
through a member of the
faculty here at Berkeley?
As far as I know. As
far as I know, yes.
But there-there may have been
more than one person involved.
Gentlemen, if I... if
I seem uncooperative,
I think you can understand
that's because of my insistence
in not getting innocent
people into trouble.
You're trying
to protect your friend.
Who's protecting you?
Well, you could.
If you gave me the name.
If you order me to, I'll do it.
That's a mistake, Robert.
You need to volunteer this name.
And did he
give you the name?
He did.
- But not then, did he?
- No.
No. In fact, it was some
months later, wasn't it?
It was.
You see me as persistent.
Well, you are...
you are persistent,
but that is your job.
And-and my job is to protect
the people that work for me.
Instead of us
going on certain steps,
which may come to
your attention...
and be disturbing to you,
I would like to discuss
those with you first.
I'm not formulating a plan.
I'll just have to
digest the whole thing.
In the months in
between your interview
with Dr. Oppenheimer and his
eventual naming of Chevalier,
did you expend resources
trying to find the name
of the intermediary?
Considerable resources, yes.
Without the name, our job
was extremely difficult.
And when did you
receive the name?
I was gone by the time
-Oppenheimer finally offered it up.
-Gone?
They felt my time would
be better spent in Europe
determining the status
of the Nazi bomb project.
Who did?
General Groves.
He transferred me to London.
It's a little early
for a Christmas party.
Something's up.
Tolman's been away.
Where?
Ruth won't tell.
Hey!
Come on, Ruthie.
Can't tell me, who can you tell?
Compartmentalization,
Oppie.
What makes you think I
know where he is anyway?
'Cause you
do a pretty good job
of knowing where Mr. Tolman
is when it counts.
Like now?
Attention!
Early Christmas
present for you all.
The British pilots
put me in the bomb bay.
Showed me the-the
oxygen, you know,
but I messed it up.
Uh, when they opened me up in
Scotland, I was unconscious.
But I pretended
I'd been napping.
Please enjoy your party.
Is
it big enough?
To end the war?
To end all war.
Uh, Heisenberg sought
me out in Copenhagen.
It was chilling,
my old student
working for the Nazis.
He told me some
things to draw me out.
Sustained fission
reactions in uranium.
That sounds more like
a reactor than a bomb.
Did he mention
gaseous diffusion?
He seemed more focused
on heavy water.
As a moderator?
Yes, instead of graphite.
What?
He took a wrong turn.
We're ahead. And with you
here to help us, Niels.
Sorry, could you...
could you give us a
moment, gentlemen?
I am not here to help, Robert.
I knew you could
do this without me.
Then why did you come?
To talk about after.
The power you're about to reveal
will forever outlive the Nazis.
And the world is not prepared.
"You could lift the stone
without being ready for
the snake that's revealed."
We have to make the
politicians understand,
this isn't a new weapon.
It's a new world.
I'll be out there doing
what I can, but you...
you're an American Prometheus.
The man who gave them the power
to destroy themselves,
and they'll respect that.
And your work really begins.
I'm sorry, Oppie,
but there's a call.
From San Francisco.
Robert!
Robert?
Robert. Robert.
God, what's the matter?
What happened?
Her father called.
They found her
yesterday in the bath.
Who?
She'd taken pills.
Left a note, not signed.
She took barbiturates,
but there was chloral
hydrate in her blood.
There was a note.
Jean Tatlock?
We were together.
She said she needed me. I...
I told her I... I
wouldn't...
I told her I couldn't...
No, it was... it was me.
You don't get to commit the sin
and then have us all
feel sorry for you
that it had consequences.
You pull yourself together.
You know, people
here depend on you.
Donald, would you like
to contribute here?
Please, help me out.
You're
on your own, pal.
Bob, I'm not quitting my job
because plutonium
is radioactive.
We just don't know
what it might do
to the female
reproductive system...
Your reproductive system is more
exposed than mine, presumably.
Can we please? The
implosion device is nowhere.
Hey, you can't rush everything.
- Oppie, please.
- Well, there's rushing
and there's getting on
with it, so pick one.
Wait. Neddermeyer's
doing his job.
Teller's not helping.
You're not helping.
I've been asking
for calculations
on the implosion
lenses for weeks.
The British can do it. Fuchs.
Absolutely.
It's your job, Teller.
I'm engaged in research.
On a hydrogen bomb
we're not even building.
I won't work for that man.
Let him go. He's a prima donna.
I agree. He
should leave Los Alamos.
Okay.
Kisty, you replace Neddermeyer.
Seth, I'm putting
you on plutonium.
Lilli, you go work for
Kisty. Because he needs you.
Fuchs, you take Teller's role.
I'm putting you exclusively
on the implosion device.
And no one is
leaving Los Alamos.
- They won't let me leave.
- No.
I won't let you leave.
Forget Hans. Forget fission.
Stay here, research
what you want.
Fusion, the hydrogen
bomb, whatever.
We'll meet to discuss.
You don't have time to meet.
You're a politician now, Robert.
You've left physics behind
many, many years ago.
Once a week.
One hour. You and me.
Now raise this fucking barrier.
So the Super
was under development
on your watch at Los Alamos?
Yes.
And yet, after the war,
you tried to deny it was viable.
No, no, no. I...
I pointed out technical
difficulties with it.
You... Didn't you try to
kill it at the AEC meeting
- after the Russian bomb test?
- No.
But that was the
recommendation of the AEC,
- was it not?
- After hours of discussion
about the best response.
An H-bomb is 1,000 times
the power of an A-bomb.
Its only intended target
would be the largest cities.
It's a weapon of mass genocide.
Izzy, draw some circles
on this side of the map
where they would target us.
- Starting with New York. D.C.
- That's fair.
It's a weapon of attack
with no defensive value.
- Deterrence.
- "Deterrence"?
Do we really need
more deterrence
than our current
arsenal of atomic bombs?
Y-You drown in ten feet
of water or-or 10,000,
what's the difference?
We can already drown
Russia. They know it.
- And now they can drown us.
- So we're just escalating...
As I said, Teller's
designs are still as
impractical as they
were during the war.
A hydrogen bomb can be made
to work, Oppie, you know that.
I don't believe we should commit
all our resources
to that chance.
Then how would you have Truman
reassure the American people?
Simply by limiting the
spread of atomic weapons
through international
control on nuclear energy.
By which you mean
world government?
The United Nations as
Roosevelt intended.
Well, I... I asked what
Truman should do, right?
The world's changed, it's
not fascism but Communism
that now threatens our survival.
Lewis, do you understand,
if we build a hydrogen bomb,
the Russians will have no
choice but to build their own?
Could they be working
on one already?
Based on information gathered
from a spy at Los Alamos.
No spy at Los Alamos.
- Gentlemen.
- There wasn't?
Let's not get sidetracked.
I say we use this moment
to gain concessions
from the Russians
by committing that we will
not build a hydrogen bomb.
Thereby revealing its existence.
Which you seem convinced
they already know.
All right.
At this point, I'd like
the committee members
to meet in privacy to
finalize our recommendations.
I'm just not sure you
want to go down this road.
Lewis, with respect, we
are the advisory committee,
we will give them our advice.
Good night.
Dr. Oppenheimer?
Hi. William Borden.
Joint Committee
on Atomic Energy?
Oh, yes, yes.
During the war, I was a pilot.
One night, flying
back from a raid,
I saw an amazing
sight like a meteor.
A V-2 rocket headed to England.
I can't help but
imagine what it will be
for such an enemy rocket
to carry an atomic warhead.
Well, let's make sure
we're not the ones
to make that possible.
Oppie, I don't think you want
to go up against Strauss.
If we both speak,
they listen to me.
When you speak,
they hear a prophet.
When Strauss speaks,
they hear themselves.
They'll listen to a prophet.
A prophet can't be
wrong. Not once.
Didn't
you accuse Oppenheimer
of sabotaging the
development of the Super?
I was never one of those
to bandy around terms
like "sabotage."
But
Mr. Borden was?
As I understand it, possibly.
How was Mr. Borden
able to put together
such a detailed indictment?
He was no longer a
government employee,
yet he appears to have
had unlimited access
to Dr. Oppenheimer's file.
Might Mr. Nichols have given
him access to the file?
Or someone else, at the AEC?
That's a very serious
accusation, Senator.
Is it your intention to
suggest that Dr. Oppenheimer
is disloyal to
the United States?
I've always assumed,
and still assume,
that he's loyal to
the United States.
I believe this. And
I shall believe it
until I see very conclusive
proof to the opposite.
Do you or
do you not believe
that Dr. Oppenheimer
is a security risk?
And if I may,
when Hitler blew his
brains out in that bunker,
it's my humble opinion
that there is no need
for that bomb to
be seen anywhere
except for that test site.
But we at least
have to take a moment
to think about whether the means
justify the ends any
longer, because...
Germany is about to surrender.
It's no longer the enemy
who are the greatest threat
to mankind, it's our work.
Hitler's dead, it's true.
But the Japanese fight on.
Their defeat seems assured.
Not if you're a G.I.
preparing to invade.
We can end this war.
But
how do we justify
using this weapon
on human beings?
We're theorists, yes?
Yes. Yep.
We imagine a future and
our imaginings horrify us.
But they won't fear it
until they understand it,
and they won't understand
it until they've used it.
When the world learns
the terrible secret
of Los Alamos,
our work here will ensure a
peace mankind has never seen.
A peace based on the kind
of international cooperation
that Roosevelt always envisaged.
Progress?
Two years and a
billion dollars' worth?
Well, hard to put a price on it.
Not really, just
add up the bills.
"Rural free deliveries."
Eighty babies delivered
the first year.
This year, we've
had ten a month.
Birth control is a little out
of my jurisdiction, General.
- Clearly.
- General.
Head down, everyone.
Fuchs, head down.
Hmm?
That's the one.
Two viable bombs. I need a date.
September.
July.
That's the sweet
spot, gentlemen.
August.
July.
Test in July.
But I need my brother.
Frank knows the desert,
he's left politics behind,
he's been working with
Lawrence for two years now.
What do we call the test?
"Batter my heart,
three-person'd god."
What?
Trinity.
You insisted
on bringing on
your brother Frank,
- a known Communist.
- A former Communist.
You brought a known
former Communist
onto America's most secret
and important defense project.
I knew my brother could
be trusted. Absolutely.
And you felt your
judgment was sound
on who on the team
could be trusted?
Fuchs, head down.
Okay, everybody ready?
Hmm?
Oh.
Well, I hope you
learned something.
Yeah, we learned we're gonna
need to be a lot further away.
Well, figure it out. Fast.
We leave for Washington
in the morning.
We're gonna give them a date.
You're a long way
from Chicago, Leo.
If we don't act now,
they're going to use
this thing against Japan.
We booked a meeting with Truman,
but somebody killed it.
You're meeting the
Secretary of War.
Just because we're building it,
doesn't mean we get to
decide how it's used.
History will judge us, Robert.
In Chicago, we put
together a petition.
I'm not... I'm not
getting into that.
Just tell me your concerns,
and I'll relay them.
My concerns?
Germany's defeated.
Japan's not going
to hold out alone.
How could you know that?
You got us into this.
You and Einstein with
your letter to Roosevelt
- saying we could build a bomb.
- Against Germany.
That's not how weapons
manufacture works, Szilard.
Oppie,
you have to help.
Fermi's
in the meeting.
- Lawrence is in the meeting.
- They're not you.
You're the great
salesman of science.
You can convince
anyone of anything.
Even yourself.
'Scuse me.
The firestorm in Tokyo
killed 100,000 people.
Mostly civilians.
I worry about an America
where we do these things
and no one protests.
Pearl Harbor and three years of
brutal conflict in the Pacific
bought us a lot of latitude
with the American public.
Enough to
unleash the atomic bomb?
Uh, the A-bomb
might not cause
as much damage as
the Tokyo bombings.
What are we estimating?
In a medium-size city, uh,
20 or 30,000 dead.
Yes, but, uh,
don't underestimate the
psychological impact of a...
of an atomic explosion.
A pillar of fire
10,000 feet tall.
Deadly neutron effects for
a mile, in all directions,
from one single device.
Dropped from a
barely noticed B-29,
the atomic bomb will be
a terrible revelation
of divine power.
If that's true, it
would be definitive.
World War II would be over.
Our boys would come home.
Military targets?
Uh, there aren't any big enough.
Perhaps a vital war plant
with workers housed nearby.
And we could issue a warning
to reduce civilian casualties.
They'd send everything
they have up against us,
and I'd be up in that plane.
But if we announce it
and it fails to go off,
we'd scupper any chance
of a Japanese surrender.
Is there no way to
demonstrate a bomb to Japan
to provoke surrender?
We intend to demonstrate it
in the most unambiguous terms.
Twice.
Once to show the weapon's power
and a second to show that
we can keep doing this
until they surrender.
We have a list of 12
cities to choose from...
Sorry, 11.
I've taken Kyoto off the list
due to its cultural significance
to the Japanese people.
Also, my wife and I
honeymooned there.
It's a magnificent city.
Let me make this simple
for you, gentlemen.
According to my intelligence,
which I cannot share with you,
the Japanese people
will not surrender
under any circumstances
short of a successful and total
invasion of the home islands.
Many lives will be lost,
American and Japanese.
The use of the atomic
bomb on Japanese cities
will save lives.
If we retain moral advantage.
- How so?
- Well, if we use this weapon
without informing our allies,
they'll see it as a threat.
And we'll be in an arms race.
How open can we be
with the Soviets?
Secrecy won't
stop the Soviets
from becoming part
of the atomic world.
We've been told they
have no uranium.
You've been misinformed.
A Russian bomb is
a matter of time.
The program needs to continue
at full pace after the war.
Uh, Secretary
Stimson, if I may...
Not all scientists on the
project are in agreement.
In fact, this might be a moment
to consider other opinions.
- If you talk a scientist in...
- The Manhattan Project
has been plagued from the start
by certain scientists
of doubtful discretion
and uncertain loyalty.
One of them just tried to
meet with the president.
Now, we need these men,
but as soon as it's practical,
we should sever any such
scientists from the program.
Wouldn't you agree, Doctor?
If a Russian
bomb is inevitable,
perhaps we should invite their
top scientists to Trinity.
President Truman
has no intention
of raising expectations
that Stalin be included
in the atomic project.
Informing him of
our breakthrough
and presenting it as
a means to win the war
need not make
unkeepable promises.
But the Potsdam peace
conference in July
will be President
Truman's last chance
to have that conversation.
Can you give us a
working bomb by then?
Absolutely. We will test
fire before the conference.
Ground zero
observation posts
at 10,000 yards
north, south and west.
- Where do we trigger from?
- Uh, south 10,000.
And base camp is ten
miles south, here.
And there's a further
observation post
on-on that hill 20 miles away.
What's that, Frank? Trigger
lines already went in.
The Air Force requested a
line of lights for their B-29.
What B-29? Our
bomb's on the tower.
They want
to use the test
to confirm a safe
operating distance.
That's risky.
Not as risky as
dropping one over Japan
and hoping that we were
right about the blast radius.
Don't let them slow us down,
we're firing on the 15th.
- The 15th? That's not...
- The 15th.
The 15th.
So I'll be here
at South Observation point
with Frank and Kistiakowsky.
You'll all be
assigned to Base Camp,
West Observation
or Far Observation.
Whoa, whoa. Careful
with the knife.
There, carefully.
Are those safe distances?
They're based on
your calculations.
Time to stand behind your
science, Hans. Literally.
Yeah.
What 'bout the radiation cloud?
Without high winds,
it should settle within
two to three miles.
Evacuation measures
are in place.
But we need good
weather for visibility,
so it has to be fine.
Everybody out.
We go on the night of the 15th.
It's a hard deadline,
so if anyone has
anything, speak now.
Okay, stop, stop.
Everybody, mattresses.
Put the mattress underneath.
Could use a final
implosion test.
It couldn't hurt.
Do it.
Is there anything else
that might stop us?
It's happening, isn't it?
I'll send a message.
If it's gone our way,
take in the sheets.
Robert?
Break a leg.
Oppie's taken a very
modest three kilotons.
- Teller's in with 45.
- 20.
Twenty thousand tons of TNT,
and does anyone
want the side action
on atmospheric ignition?
Are you saying
we'll have to delay?
I'm saying it would be prudent.
This weather, has
it reached the site?
Bethe is calling to tell you
the implosion test failed.
Hello, Hans.
Yes, he's here.
Yes.
- Is he wrong?
- No.
- No?
So we're about to fire a dud?
- No.
- Explain.
Well, I can't. I
just... I-I just know.
I know the implosion
lenses will work.
If we fire these detonators
and they don't
trigger a reaction,
two years' worth of plutonium
will be scattered
across White Sands.
A month of my salary against
ten bucks says it lights.
Jesus.
The wind's picking
up at zero, not the rain.
Lightning's circling.
You think it might be
time to tell your men
to get away from the steel
tower with the atomic bomb?
Let's get to South Observation.
Pull 'em out.
We can make our
determination there.
The team hasn't
slept in two nights.
If we stand down,
make the bomb safe,
we won't be back here for weeks.
Then we'll miss Potsdam.
I gotta get word
to Truman by 7:00.
Our window's closing.
What is this doing?
Raining, blowing, lightning.
- For how long, damn it?
- It's holdin' strong.
It'll break before dawn.
- How could you know that?
- I know this desert.
Storm cools overnight.
Just before dawn,
the storm breaks.
He could be right, but
schedule as late as possible.
5:30!
Sign your forecast.
If you're wrong, I'll hang you.
Frank, tell them all, 5:30.
- 5:30, 5:30.
- 5:30.
Three years, 4,000
people, $2 billion.
Well, if it doesn't
go off...
we're both finished.
I'm betting on three kilotons.
Anything less, they
won't get what it is.
What did Fermi mean by
"atmospheric ignition"?
Well, we had a moment
where it looked like
the chain reaction from an
atomic device might never stop.
Setting fire to the atmosphere.
Why is Fermi still
taking side bets on it?
Call it gallows humor.
Wait, are we saying
there's a chance
that when we push that button,
we destroy the world?
Nothing in our research
over three years
supports that conclusion.
Except as the most
remote possibility.
How remote?
Chances are near zero.
Near zero?
What do you want
from theory alone?
Zero would be nice.
In exactly
one hour, 58 minutes,
we'll know.
It's letting up.
The arming party's left Zero,
they're heading this way.
Throwing the switches.
Turn the cars.
Ready for emergency evacuation.
Welder's glass.
Everybody take your places.
Everybody take a welder's glass.
Twenty minutes.
That's 20.
On the leg, please.
- Feynman.
- No.
The glass. Stops the U.V.
And what stops the glass?
I'm gonna head to base
camp. Best of luck.
Robert.
Try not to blow up the world.
Watch that needle.
If the detonators don't charge
or the voltage drops
below one volt,
you hit that button, you abort.
- Understood?
- Understood.
Two
minutes to detonation.
Everybody down.
Do not turn around
until you see light
reflected on the hills.
Then look at the explosion
only through your
welder's glass.
Ninety
seconds to detonation.
Ninety seconds to detonation.
Is it rubbed in?
Yeah.
Sixty
seconds to detonation.
These things are
hard on your heart.
Thirty seconds.
Detonators charged.
Seventeen, sixteen,
fifteen,
fourteen,
thirteen,
twelve,
eleven,
ten,
nine,
eight,
seven,
six...
five...
four...
three...
two...
one.
Poof.
"And now
I am become Death.
The destroyer of worlds."
It worked.
- You owe me ten dollars!
- Oh!
- Come on!
- Hang on.
I'm good for it, Kisty.
You are.
Yes, you are!
Well done.
We did it! We did it!
- Get me Potsdam right away.
- Yes, sir.
Get a message to Kitty.
We can't say anything.
Tell her to take in the sheets.
We did it, everyone!
Hello?
- Hi, Kitty?
- What, what? Charlotte...
Charlotte, go ahead, go ahead.
Oh, um, well, I don't know,
he just said to tell you
to "bring in the sheets."
Kitty?
Kitty? Kitty, are
you still there?
If they detonate
it too high in the air,
the blast won't be as powerful.
With respect, Dr. Oppenheimer,
we'll take it from here.
Did Truman brief
Stalin at Potsdam?
A brief would be
an overstatement.
He referred to a
powerful new weapon.
Stalin hoped we'd
use it against Japan.
That's it?
Robert, we've given them an ace,
it's for them to play the hand.
You're aiming for the 6th?
It's up to the CO
in the Pacific.
Shall I come with
you to Washington?
What for?
Well, you'll keep me informed.
Of course.
As best I can.
Would the Japanese surrender
if they knew what was coming?
I don't know.
Have you seen
Szilard's petition?
What the hell does Szilard
know about the Japanese?
You're not signing it, are you?
Many people have. A
lot of people have.
Edward.
The fact that we built this bomb
does not give us any more...
any more right or responsibility
to decide how it's
used than anyone else.
But we're the only
people who know about it.
I've told Stimson the various
opinions of the community.
But what's your opinion?
Once it's used...
nuclear war, perhaps all war...
becomes unthinkable.
Until somebody
builds a bigger bomb.
I thought they would call.
It's only the 5th.
In Japan, it's the 6th.
Charlotte.
Try Groves.
Anything?
Charlotte?
Truman's
on the radio.
Sixteen hours ago,
an American airplane dropped
one bomb on Hiroshima...
and destroyed its
usefulness to the enemy.
The bomb had more power
than 20,000 tons of TNT.
It is an atomic bomb.
It is a harnessing
of the basic powers
of the universe.
Groves on one.
We are now prepared
to destroy more rapidly
and completely the Japanese...
General?
I'm very proud of
you and all of your people.
It went all right?
Apparently, it went
with a tremendous bang.
Well,
everyone here is feeling
reasonably good about it.
It's been a long road.
I think one of the
wisest things I ever did
was when I selected the
director of Los Alamos.
We have spent
more than $2 billion
on the greatest scientific
gamble in history,
and we have won.
Oppie! Oppie! Oppie!
Oppie! Oppie!
Oppie! Oppie! Oppie! Oppie!
Oppie! Oppie! Oppie!
Oppie! Oppie!
Oppie! Oppie! Oppie! Oppie!
The world...
will remember this day.
It's too soon to...
It's too soon to determine
what the results
of the bombing are.
But I'll bet the
Japanese didn't like it.
I'm so proud.
So proud of what you
have accomplished.
I just wish we had it in time
to use against the Germans.
Dr. Oppenheimer?
- Nice picture.
- Oh.
President Truman
will see you now.
Dr. Oppenheimer. It's an honor.
- Mr. President.
- Please.
Thank you.
Secretary Byrnes.
How's it feel to be
the most famous
man in the world?
You helped save a lot
of American lives.
What we did at
Hiroshima was a...
And Nagasaki.
Well, obviously.
Your invention let us
bring our boys home.
Well, it was hardly
my invention.
It was you on the cover of Time.
Jim tells me you're concerned
about an arms race
with the Soviets.
Uh, yes, uh...
Well, um,
it's that, uh, now is
our chance to secure
international cooperation on
atomic energy,
and... and I'm concerned...
Do you know when the Soviets
are gonna have the bomb?
I don't think I could give a...
Never.
Mr. President, the-the
Russians have good physicists
and-and... and
abundant resources.
- Abundant?
- Yes.
I don't think so.
Well, they'll-they'll put
everything they have and...
I hear you're
leaving Los Alamos.
What should we do with it?
Give it back to the Indians.
Um... Dr. Oppenheimer,
if what you say about
the Soviets is true,
we have to build up Los Alamos,
not shut it down.
Uh, Mr. President...
Um...
I feel that I have
blood on my hands.
You think anyone in
Hiroshima or Nagasaki
gives a shit who built the bomb?
They care who dropped it.
I did.
Hiroshima isn't about you.
Dr. Oppenheimer.
Don't let that
crybaby back in here.
Robert saw that
hand-wringing got him nowhere.
By the time I'd met
him, he'd fully embraced
his "father of the
bomb" reputation.
Used his profile to
influence policy.
Doctor, in the
years following the war,
would you say that you
exerted a great influence
on the atomic
policies of the USA?
I think great
would be an overstatement.
Really? If we look
at the issue of isotopes,
were you not
personally responsible
for destroying all
opposition to their export?
Could use a-a bottle of beer...
when making atomic
weapons. In fact, you do.
I was the spokesman,
but the-the opinion
among scientists was unanimous.
All along with
McCarthy on the rise,
he knew he was vulnerable.
His brother was blacklisted
by every university
in the country.
Lomanitz wound up working
the railroad, laying track.
And Chevalier went into exile.
But none of that
stopped Robert from
pushing the GAC
to recommend arms control
instead of the H-bomb.
He was devastated
when Truman rejected
their recommendation.
I miss Richard more
than I can bear.
I know, Ruth, I know.
Part of me's glad he didn't live
to see where this is all going.
Here comes
the birthday boy.
- To gloat.
- Have fun.
Robert, uh, my son and his
fiancée are desperate to meet
the father of the
atomic bomb, and so...
Well. Good day.
Is this a bad time?
What do you think, Lewis?
Well, I think it must
have been a blow for you.
For the world.
The world?
What does Fuchs mean to
the rest of the world?
Fuchs?
Klaus Fuchs?
Oh, dear. You haven't heard.
Klaus Fuchs, the British
scientist that you put
onto the implosion
team at Los Alamos,
turns out he was...
he was spying for the
Soviets the whole time.
I'm sorry.
After the truth
about Fuchs came out,
the FBI stepped up
surveillance on him.
He knew his phone was tapped,
he was followed everywhere...
his trash picked through.
But never stopped
speaking his mind.
A man of conviction.
And maybe he thought fame
could actually protect him.
When Eisenhower took office,
he saw one more chance.
He took it.
America and Russia
may be likened to two
scorpions in a bottle,
each capable of
killing the other
but only at the risk
of his own life.
Now, there are various
aspects of this policy...
Lot of
scientists blame me,
but how was I supposed
to protect him?
Too secret for discussion,
candor is the only remedy.
Officials in Washington
need to start leveling
with the American people.
That was the last straw
for Robert's enemies.
So he had to lose his
security clearance.
And with it, his credibility.
But how could they do it?
He was a war hero.
He'd already told
everyone about his past.
Borden dredged it all up.
How could Borden get access
to Oppenheimer's FBI file?
Could it have been Nichols?
No, I can't imagine
he'd do that.
But whoever did
unleashed a firestorm
that burned a path
from the White House
back to my desk at the AEC.
You see them in there, right?
I've been working my
whole life to get here.
Cabinet of the United
States of America.
Now, in front of
the entire country,
they're gonna put
me back in my place.
A lowly shoe salesman.
Lewis, we can win this thing.
I-I think we can get
the Senate to grasp
that you did your duty,
painful though it was.
Now, will Hill's
testimony back us up?
- Hill will be fine.
- I don't really know him,
but, uh, he was one of
Szilard's boys in Chicago,
and they never forgave
Robert for not supporting
their petition
against bombing Japan.
This was taken 31 days
after the bombing.
Virtually everyone
in the street,
for nearly a mile around,
was instantly and
seriously burned.
The, uh, Japanese spoke of
people who wore striped clothing
upon whom the skin
was burned in stripes.
There were many who
thought themselves lucky,
who climbed out of the
ruins of their homes
only slightly injured.
But they died anyway.
They died days or weeks later
from the radium-like rays
emitted in great numbers
at the moment of the explosion.
Did you read this
crap in the papers?
A British physicist is
saying the atomic bombings
were not the last
act of World War II
but the first act of this
cold war with Russia.
Which physicist?
I think you knew him.
Patrick Blackett.
He may not be wrong.
Stimson is now telling me
we bombed an enemy that
was essentially defeated.
Robert, you've
all the influence now.
Please.
Urge them to continue my
research on the Super.
I neither can nor will, Edward.
Why not?
It's not the right
use of our resources.
Is that what you really believe?
J. Robert Oppenheimer.
Sphinx-like guru of the atom.
Nobody knows what you believe.
Do you? Hmm?
One final time,
our program director,
Dr. J. Robert Oppenheimer.
I hope that
in years to come
you will look back on
your work here with pride.
But today, that pride
must be tempered
with a profound concern.
If atomic weapons
are to be added
to the arsenals of
a warring world,
then the day will come
when people will curse
the name of Los Alamos.
Uh, sorry, Admiral.
Stopped off to get this.
It seems pretty favorable.
There's Oppenheimer.
What's the caption?
Uh, "J. Robert Oppenheimer,
Strauss fought..."
"and the US won."
That'll work.
Those were your words
from the other day.
We needed to pivot.
But how would you know
what Time magazine's
gonna write?
Henry Luce is a friend.
You sat here and let me
tell you how it's done,
but you've been far
ahead all along.
Survival in Washington
is about knowing how
to get things done.
Right.
What was it you
said about Borden?
"Why get caught holding
the knife yourself?"
I'm beginning to think Borden
was holding the knife for you.
It's gonna come down
to how much influence
Borden's been able
to exert on Teller.
Did I say something funny?
Just "Borden, Borden, Borden"
when we all know
that it's Strauss.
Lewis brought me to
Princeton, Kitty.
And then you humiliated
him in front of Congress.
But more useful than a sandwich.
- How'd I do?
- I'll call recess,
ten minutes.
Maybe a little too well, Robert.
That was six years ago.
You know, the truly vindictive,
patient as saints.
Strauss has been perfectly
clear that he is neutral.
Wake up. It is Strauss.
It's always been
Strauss, and you know it.
Why won't you fight him?
Christ's sake.
It wasn't Nichols or Hoover
or one of Truman's
guys. It was you.
You gave the file to Borden.
You set him on Oppenheimer.
- You convinced him to...
- Borden...
Didn't
take any convincing.
Take your time,
use the entire file.
Write up your conclusion,
send them to the FBI.
The material is
obviously extensive,
but there's nothing new here.
Your
conclusions will be.
And they'll have to be answered.
Hoover passes them to McCarthy?
Oppenheimer's too slippery
for that self-promoting clown.
I've talked it over with Hoover,
he'll hold McCarthy at bay
while you do this with the AEC.
- A trial.
- No.
No trial. You can't give
Oppenheimer a platform.
You can't martyr him.
We need a systematic destruction
of Oppenheimer's credibility
so he can never again speak on
matters of national security.
Then what?
A shabby little room,
far from the limelight.
A simple
bureaucratic procedure.
His Q clearance
is up for renewal.
You send your
accusations to the FBI.
Hoover sends them to the
AEC, you're forced to act.
You write up an indictment
and tell Oppenheimer
his security clearance
is not being renewed.
But offer him the
chance to appeal.
As you can see, Robert,
it's not yet signed.
May I keep this?
No.
If you do decide to appeal,
they'll have to send you a copy.
When he appeals... and
trust me, he will...
I appoint a board.
They will, of
course, have counsel.
- Prosecutor?
- In all but name.
- Who?
- Roger Robb.
Ouch.
Robb will have
security clearance
to examine Oppenheimer's file.
As will the Gray board.
Defense counsel will not.
A closed hearing.
The so-called
derogatory information
in your indictment of me.
No audience. No reporters.
- No burden of proof.
- No burden of proof?
We're not convicting.
We're just denying.
What is it you said?
"This is just how
the game is played."
Well, forgive my naivete.
Amateurs seek the sun.
Get eaten.
Power stays in the shadows.
But, sir, you're... you're
out of the shadows now.
Yeah, that's why
this has to work.
Well...
Teller's testifying
this morning.
That'll help. And then...
Hill is in the afternoon.
Hill is gonna help us too.
As you can see,
Robert, it's not yet signed.
May I keep this?
No.
If you do decide to appeal,
then they'll have
to send you a copy.
Take my car and
driver. I insist.
I'll have to consult
my lawyers, Lewis.
Of course. But
don't take too long.
I can't keep Nichols at bay.
I'm sorry it's come
to this, Robert.
I think it's wrong.
Nichols
wants me to fight
so he can get it
all on the record.
Strauss wants me to walk away.
Strauss knows that
you can't do that,
you'd be accepting the charges.
You'll lose your job.
You will lose your reputation.
We'll lose our house.
Robert, we have to fight.
As AEC Counsel,
I can't represent you.
I'll call Lloyd Garrison.
Oh, he's good.
The best, but I
have to warn you...
this won't be a fair fight.
During your interview
with Boris Pash in 1943,
did you refer to microfilm?
- No.
- Tab 11,
page one, paragraph
three. You never said,
"Man at the consulate expert
in the use of microfilm"?
- I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
- No.
I would like to
know what document
Mr. Robb is quoting from
and if we might be
furnished with a copy.
The document is
classified, Mr. Garrison.
I think we should get back
to first-hand information.
This is first-hand.
How so, Roger?
There was a recording
of the interview.
You let
my client sit here
and potentially perjure himself,
and all this time,
you had a recording?
Nobody told your client
to misrepresent
his former answers.
Misrepre... It-it
was 12 years ago.
Can we hear this recording?
You don't have the
clearance, Mr. Garrison.
But you're reading
it into the record.
Please, please.
Is this proceeding interested
in entrapment or in truth?
If it's truth, where's
the disclosure?
Where's the witness list?
Mr. Garrison, this isn't a
trial, as you are well aware.
Evidentiary rules do not apply.
We are dealing with
national security.
Yes, sir, with all due respect,
I fail to see how
national security
prevents the prosecution
from providing us
- with a list of witnesses.
- Perhaps we are in need
- of a brief recess.
- Gentlemen,
you have my words.
If you say they're from a
transcript, then I'll accept it.
I've already explained I made
up a cock-and-bull story.
But why would anyone make
up such an elaborate story?
Because I was an idiot.
Why lie?
Well, clearly with the
intention of not revealing
who the intermediary was.
Your friend, Haakon
Chevalier, the Communist.
Is he still your friend?
Yes.
Dr. Rabi,
thank you for coming.
Do you know who else the
prosecution has called?
Teller, obviously.
They've asked Lawrence.
What did he say?
He wasn't going to
help them, but...
But?
Strauss told him that
you and Ruth Tolman
have been having an
affair for years.
The whole time you lived
with them in Pasadena.
He convinced Lawrence
that Richard died
of a broken heart.
That's absurd.
- What part?
- The broken heart.
Richard never found out.
Is Lawrence gonna testify?
I don't know.
Dr. Rabi,
what governmental positions
do you currently hold?
I am the chairman of the
General Advisory Committee
to the AEC, succeeding
Dr. Oppenheimer.
And how long have
you known Dr. Oppenheimer?
Since 1928.
I... I know him quite well.
Well enough to
speak to the bearing
of his loyalty and character?
Dr. Oppenheimer is a man
of upstanding character.
And he is loyal to
the United States,
to his friends,
to the institutions
of which he is part.
Eat.
What was that?
Nothing to worry about.
After the
Russian A-bomb test,
did Dr. Lawrence come to see
you about the hydrogen bomb?
You'd be better off asking him.
Well, I fully intend to.
Would you say that
Dr. Oppenheimer was
unalterably opposed
to the H-bomb?
No, he-he thought
that a fusion program
would come at the expense of our
awfully good fission program.
But that proved
not to be the case.
In the event both could be done.
Suppose that this board
did not feel satisfied
that in his testimony here,
Dr. Oppenheimer had
been wholly truthful.
What would you say whether
or not he should be cleared?
Why go through all
this against a man
who has accomplished
what Dr. Oppenheimer has?
Look at his record.
We have an A-bomb and
a whole series of it.
We have a whole
series of Super bombs.
What more do you want?
Mermaids?
But I've known
Secretary Strauss
for many years,
and I feel it a necessity
to express the warm support
for science and scientists
Lewis has shown.
We'll break now,
unless there's any
immediate business.
Senator, I'd
like to once again request
that we're furnished
with a list of witnesses.
And I will remind the
nominee that we don't always
have that information
in advance.
We do know that Dr. Hill
will be here after lunch.
Mr. Chairman, our next
scheduled witness,
Dr. Lawrence, has apparently
come down with colitis.
So we'll proceed with
William Borden instead.
Mr. Borden, welcome.
Please take a seat.
Mr. Borden,
during your investigation
into Dr. Oppenheimer,
did you reach
certain conclusions?
- I did.
- And did there come a time
when you expressed
those conclusions
in a letter to
Mr. J. Edgar Hoover
of the Federal Bureau
of Investigation?
- That is correct.
- Prior to the writing
of the letter, did you discuss
the writing of the letter
with anybody attached to the
Atomic Energy Commission?
I did not.
Thanks, and do you
have a copy of the letter?
I have one
in front of me.
Would you please be so
kind as to read it, sir?
"Dear Mr. Hoover,
the purpose of this
letter is to state..."
Uh, I'm sorry, I'm
sorry, if I could have a...
What is the purpose
of the delay?
He's simply gonna
read the letter.
Mr. Chairman,
this is the first I've
seen of this letter,
and I see statements here, uh,
at least one, of a
kind that I don't think
anyone would like to
see go into the record.
These are accusations that
have not previously been made.
That are not part of the
indictment from Nichols.
Accusations of a kind that
I don't think belong here.
The witness wrote this
letter on his own initiative,
laying out evidence that has
already been before the board.
His conclusions are
valid testimony,
just like the... the
positive conclusions
of friends of Dr. Oppenheimer.
It cuts both ways.
How long has Counsel been in
possession of this letter?
I don't think I
should be subject
to cross-examination
by you, Mr. Garrison.
Mr. Garrison, given
that we on the board
have all read the letter,
wouldn't it be better to
have it in the record?
Let's proceed.
"Dear Mr. Hoover,
"the purpose of this letter
is to state my opinion
"based upon years of study
"of the available
classified evidence,
"that more probably than not,
"J. Robert Oppenheimer is an
agent of the Soviet Union.
"The following
conclusions are justified.
"One, between 1929 and 1942,
more probably than not,
"J. Robert Oppenheimer
"was a sufficiently
hardened Communist,
"that he volunteered
information to the Soviets.
"Two, more probably than not,
"he has since been functioning
as an espionage agent.
"Three, more probably than not,
"he has since acted
under a Soviet directive
in influencing United
States military policy..."
I'm sorry, Robert.
"atomic
energy, intelligence
- and diplomatic policy."
- Is anyone
ever going to tell the truth
about what's happening here?
We will
now hear from Dr. David Hill.
Dr. Hill,
would you care to
make a statement?
Thank you.
I've been asked to testify
about Lewis Strauss.
A man who has given
years of service
in high positions of government
and who is known to be earnest,
hardworking and intelligent.
The views I have to
express are my own,
but I believe that much I have
to say will help to indicate
why most of the
scientists in this country
would prefer to see Mr. Strauss
completely out of government.
You're... You're
referring to the hostility
of certain scientists
directed toward Mr. Strauss
because of his
commitment to security
as demonstrated in the
Oppenheimer affair?
No.
Because of the
personal vindictiveness
he demonstrated against
Dr. Oppenheimer.
Order.
Order!
It appears to most scientists
around this country
that Robert Oppenheimer
is now being
pilloried and put
through an ordeal
because he expressed
his honest opinions.
Dr. Bush, I thought I
was performing a service
to my country when
hearing this case.
No board in this country
should sit in judgment of a man
because he expressed
strong opinions.
If you want to try that
case, you should try me.
Excuse me, gentlemen,
if I become stirred,
but I am.
Dr. Hill, we've already heard
that Mr. Strauss did
not bring the charges
or participate in the hearings
against Dr. Oppenheimer.
The Oppenheimer matter was
initiated and carried through
largely through the
animus of Lewis Strauss.
Oppenheimer made mincemeat
out of Strauss's position
on the shipment of
isotopes to Norway,
and Strauss never forgave
him this public humiliation.
Another controversy between
them centered around
their differences in
judgment on how the H-bomb
would contribute to
national security.
Strauss turned to the
personnel security system
in order to destroy
Oppenheimer's effectiveness,
and Strauss was able to
find a few ambitious men
who also disagreed with
Oppenheimer's positions
and envied him his prestige
in government circles.
I've always
assumed, and still assume,
that he's loyal to
the United States.
I believe this. And
I shall believe it
until I see very conclusive
proof to the opposite.
Do you or do you not believe
that Dr. Oppenheimer
is a security risk?
In a great number of cases,
I have seen Dr. Oppenheimer
act in a way
which was to me exceedingly
hard to understand.
I thoroughly disagreed with
him in numerous issues,
and his actions
frankly appeared to me
confused and complicated.
To this extent, I feel,
I want to see the vital
interest of this country
in hands which I
understand better
and therefore trust more.
- Thank you, Doctor.
- Thank you.
I'm sorry.
You shook
his fucking hand?
Oh, I would have
spit in his face.
Not sure the board would
have appreciated that.
Is it not
gentlemanly enough for you?
Well, I-I think you're all
being too goddamn gentlemanly.
Gray must see what
Robb is doing.
Why doesn't he
just shut him down?
And you shaking Teller's hand.
You need to stop
playing the martyr.
Under the current
AEC guidelines,
would you clear
Dr. Oppenheimer today?
Under my interpretation
of the Atomic Energy Act,
which did not exist
when I hired
Dr. Oppenheimer in 1942...
I would not clear him today,
uh, if I were on the commission.
Good. Thank you,
General. That is all.
But I don't think I'd
clear any of those guys.
That's all.
Dr. Oppenheimer
had no responsibility
in the selection
or the clearance
of Klaus Fuchs, did he?
No. None at all.
And you wouldn't want
to leave this board
with any suggestion today
that you're here questioning
his basic loyalty
to the United States
in the operation of Los Alamos?
By no means.
I hope I didn't lead
anyone to believe otherwise
for an instant.
Thank you, General.
Okay. We shouldn't
keep them waiting.
She'll be here.
Do you even want her here?
Only a fool or an adolescent
presumes to know someone
else's relationship,
and you're neither, Lloyd.
Kitty and I,
we're grown-ups.
We've walked through
fire together.
She'll do fine.
Would you describe
your views on Communism
as pro, anti, neutral?
Very strongly against.
I-I've had nothing to do
with Communism in... since...
since 1936, since...
since before I met Robert.
That's all.
The record demonstrates
that Oppenheimer
was not interrogated
by impartial and disinterested
counsel for the Gray board.
He was interrogated
by a prosecutor
who used all the tricks
of a rather ingenious
legal background.
You
are charging now
that the Gray board
permitted a prosecution.
If I were on the Gray board,
I would have protested
against the tactics
of the man who served, in fact,
as the prosecuting counsel.
A man appointed not by the board
but by Lewis Strauss.
Who was this?
I'm sorry?
Uh, Roger Robb.
Mrs. Oppenheimer.
Did you have a Communist
Party membership card?
I'm... I'm not sure.
Not sure?
Well...
Well?
I mean, presumably, the
act of joining the Party
required sending some money
and receiving a card, no?
Yeah.
Sorry.
Yes. Mm.
It's just it was all
so very long ago,
- Mr. Robb, wasn't it?
- Not really.
Long enough to have forgotten.
Did you return the
card or rip it up?
The card whose existence
I've forgotten?
Your Communist Party
membership card.
Haven't the slightest idea.
Can a distinction
be made between
Soviet Communism and Communism?
Well, in the days
when I was a member,
I thought they were
definitely two things.
- Oh?
- I thought that
the Communist Party
of the United States
was concerned with
our domestic problems.
I now no longer believe this.
Believe the whole
thing's linked together
and spread all over the world,
and I have believed this
since I left the Party
16 years ago.
- But...
- Seventeen years ago.
My mistake.
- But you said...
- Sorry, 18.
Eighteen years ago.
Are you
familiar with the fact
your husband was
making contributions
to the Spanish Civil
War as late as 1942?
I knew that Robert gave
money from time to time.
Did you know this
money was going
into Communist Party channels?
Don't you mean "through"?
- Pardon?
- I think you mean
"through Communist Party
channels," don't you?
- Y-Yes!
- Yes?
- Yes!
- Yes.
Then would it be fair to say
that this meant that by 1942,
your husband had not stopped
having anything to do
with the Communist Party?
You don't have to
answer that yes or no.
You can answer that
any way you wish.
I know that, thank you.
It's your question.
- It's not properly phrased.
- Do you understand
- what I'm getting at?
- I do.
Then why don't you
answer it that way?
'Cause I don't like your phrase.
"Having anything to do
with the Communist Party."
Because Robert never
had anything to do
with the Communist
Party as such.
I know he gave money
to Spanish refugees.
I know he took an
intellectual interest
in Communist ideas...
Are there two types
of Communists?
Intellectual Communists
and your plain old
regular Commie?
Well, I couldn't
answer that one.
I
couldn't either.
Evening.
Robert, you
can't win this thing.
It's a kangaroo court with
a predetermined outcome.
Why put yourself
through more of it?
I have my reasons.
All right.
Good night.
He has a point.
I'm not sure you
understand, Albert.
No?
I left my country
never to return.
You served your country well.
If this is the reward
she offers you, then...
perhaps you should
turn your back on her.
Damn it, I happen to
love this country.
Then tell them to go to hell.
Interestingly enough,
this is no longer a
confirmation hearing,
it's now a trial...
about a trial!
It's not good he's
telling everyone
you initiated the hearings.
He can't prove a goddamn thing.
He certainly can't prove that
I gave the file to Borden.
We're not in court, sir.
There's no burden of proof.
Right. They're not convicting...
just denying.
Why would Hill come
here to tear me down?
What's his angle?
Do people need a reason
to do the right thing?
- As he sees it.
- I told you,
Oppenheimer poisoned the
scientists against me,
right from that first meeting.
I don't know what Oppenheimer
said to him that day,
but Einstein wouldn't
even meet my eye.
Oppenheimer knows how
to manipulate his own.
And at Los Alamos,
he preyed on the
naivete of scientists
who thought they'd get a say
in how we used their work,
but don't ever think he
was that naive himself.
Doctor.
During your work on
the hydrogen bomb,
were you deterred
by any moral qualms?
Yes, of course.
But you still got on
with your work, didn't you?
Yes, because this was
work of exploration,
it was not the
preparation of a weapon.
You mean it was more of
a... an academic excursion.
No, it is not an academic thing
whether you can build
a hydrogen bomb.
It's a matter of life and death.
By 1942, you were
actively pushing
the development of the
hydrogen bomb, weren't you?
Pushing's not the right word.
Supporting it and
working on it, yes.
So when did these moral
qualms become so strong
that you actively opposed
the development of
the hydrogen bomb?
When it was suggested
that it be the policy
of the United States to make
these things at all cost
without regard to the
balance between these weapons
and atomic weapons as
part of our arsenal.
What do moral qualms
have to do with that?
Wha... What do moral qualms
- have to do with it?
- Yes.
Oppenheimer wanted to
own the atomic bomb.
He wanted to be the man
who moved the Earth.
He talks about putting
the nuclear genie
back in the bottle.
Well, I'm here to tell you
that I know J.
Robert Oppenheimer,
and if he could do it all
over, he'd do it all the same.
You know he's never once said
that he regrets Hiroshima?
He'd do it all over. Why?
Because it made him
the most important
man who ever lived.
Well, we've...
we've freely used
the atomic bomb...
In fact, Doctor,
you assisted in selecting
the target to drop the
atomic bomb on Japan,
- didn't you?
- Yes.
Well, then you knew,
did you not, that by dropping
that atomic bomb on the
target you selected,
that thousands of
civilians would be killed
or injured, is that correct?
Yes, not as many
as turned out...
Oh. Well, how many
were killed or injured?
- 70,000.
- 70,000
at both Hiroshima and...
110,000 at both.
On the day
of each bombing?
Yes.
And in the weeks and
years that followed?
It has been put at somewhere
between 50 and 100,000.
- 220,000 dead at least?
- Yes.
Any moral scruples about that?
Terrible ones.
But yet you testified in here
that the bombing of Hiroshima
was very successful.
- Technically successful.
- Oh!
Technically, it was
very successful.
And it is also alleged to
have helped end the war.
Would you have been in
support of the dropping
of a hydrogen bomb on Hiroshima?
That would make no sense at all.
- Why?
- The-the target is too small.
Well, supposing there had
been a target in Japan
big enough for a
thermonuclear weapon,
would you have been opposed
to the dropping of it?
This was not a problem with
which I was confronted...
Well, I'm confronting
you with it now, sir.
It was all part of his plan.
He wanted the glorious,
insincere guilt of
the self-important
to wear like a fuckin' crown.
Say, "No, we cannot
go down this road,"
even as he knew we'd have to.
Would you have been
opposed to the dropping
of a thermonuclear
weapon on Japan
- because of moral scruples?
- Yes, I believe I would, sir.
Well, did you
oppose the dropping
of an atomic bomb on Hiroshima
because of moral scruples?
We set forth our arguments...
No, you, you, you.
I'm asking you.
- I set... I set forth...
- Not we. You, you, you!
Our arguments
against dropping it,
but I did not endorse them.
You mean after
working night and day
for three years
building the bomb,
you then argued against
the use of it?
I was asked by the
Secretary of War
what the views of
scientists were.
I gave him the views
against and the views for.
You supported the dropping
of the atom bomb on Japan.
- What do you mean "support"?
- Didn't you?
- You supported it!
- What do you mean "support"?
Well, you helped pick
the target, didn't you?
I did my job.
I was not in a policy-making
position at Los Alamos.
I would have done anything
I was asked to do.
Well, then you would have
built the H-bomb too,
- wouldn't you?
- I couldn't.
I didn't ask you that, Doctor!
And the GAC report
which you co-authored
after the Soviet
atomic test said
a Super bomb should
never be built!
What we meant,
what I meant was...
- What you, who? Who?
- What I meant...
And wouldn't the
Russians do anything
to increase their strength?
If we did
it, they would have to do it.
Our efforts would only
fuel their efforts,
just as it had with
the atomic bomb.
"Just as it had with the
atomic bomb," exactly!
No moral scruples in
1945, plenty in 1949.
Dr. Oppenheimer...
when did your strong
moral convictions develop
with respect to
the hydrogen bomb?
When it became clear to me
that we would tend to
use any weapon we had.
J. Robert
Oppenheimer, the martyr.
I gave him exactly
what he wanted.
To be remembered for Trinity,
not Hiroshima,
not Nagasaki.
He should be thanking me.
Well, he's not.
Do we still have enough votes,
or is the crowning
moment of my career
about to become the most
public humiliation of my life?
Full Senate's about to vote.
You'll scrape through.
Great, then gather
the fucking press.
Dr. J.
Robert Oppenheimer.
This board, having
heard testimony from you
and many of your current
and former colleagues,
has come to the
unanimous conclusion
that you are a loyal citizen.
However,
in the light of your
continuing associations
and disregard
for the security
apparatus of this country,
together with your
somewhat disturbing conduct
on the hydrogen bomb program
and the regrettable
lack of candor
in certain of your
responses to this board,
we have voted two to one
to deny the renewal of
your security clearance.
A full written opinion, with
a dissent from Mr. Evans,
will be issued to the
AEC in the coming days.
That is all.
- Gordon...
- Roger.
Robert.
Don't...
Don't take in the sheets.
Get a
picture with him.
Sir, sir.
Two
minutes. Two minutes.
- You'll get your shot.
- Please, sir.
We've been waiting for so long.
- Evening, sir.
- Come out.
Sir, sir!
Is it official?
Well, there were,
uh, a couple of
unexpected holdouts.
I'm denied. Yeah?
- I'm afraid so, sir.
- All right.
Who were the holdouts?
Um, there were three,
led by the junior senator
from Massachusetts.
Young guy trying to
make a name for himself,
didn't like what you
did to Oppenheimer.
What's his name?
Uh, Kennedy.
John F. Kennedy.
Kitty?
Did you think that if you
let them tar and feather you,
that the world
would forgive you?
It won't.
We'll see.
Goddamn it.
You
told me I'd be okay.
Yeah, well, I didn't have
all the facts, did I?
Here's a fact.
President Eisenhower
pinned the Medal of Freedom
on my chest last year
'cause I've always done
what's right for this country.
They don't want me
in the Cabinet room?
Well, that's... that's fine.
Maybe they should just
invite Oppenheimer instead.
Maybe they will.
I told you,
he turned the scientists
against me one by one,
starting with Einstein. I
told you about, uh, Einstein.
I saw him by the pond.
You did, but you know, sir,
since nobody really knows
what they said to
each other that day,
is it possible they didn't
talk about you at all?
Is it possible they spoke
about something, uh,
more important?
Mr. Strauss!
Over here! Mr. Strauss!
Oh.
Thank you.
Albert.
Ah.
The man of the moment.
You once held a-a
reception for me.
In Berkeley. You
gave me an award.
- Hmm?
- Yes.
You all thought that
I had lost the ability
to understand what I'd started.
So the award really
wasn't for me,
it was for all of you, hmm?
Now it's your turn
to deal with the consequences
of your achievement.
And one day,
when they've punished
you enough...
they'll serve you
salmon and potato salad.
Make speeches...
give you a medal.
Hello, Frank.
You're happy, I'm happy.
Pat you on the back,
tell you all is forgiven.
Just remember...
it won't be for you.
It'll be for them.
Albert.
When I came to you with
those calculations,
we thought we might
start a chain reaction
that would destroy
the entire world.
Mm, I remember it well.
What of it?
I believe we did.